That if you guys make it at least even
just halfway through this video,
you're going to change something within
your business.
I can almost 100% tell you that. Now,
we're going to go
through most things personal brand today,
which I didn't really know
what I was doing for the first few years.
That sounds really weird to say it,
but all of us are going to be building
something in person.
We might not even know it or not, and
that thing is going to
enable us to sell,
to get people to trust us,
to get people to use our services
online.
The majority of you will probably be
personal trainers.
There'll be some of you in similar fields,
maybe physio, accountants,
whatever. Now, there
is quite a few bits to get through.
I'm going to make this as interesting as
possible, and we're going to be
interactive,
and you guys get to ask me questions.
You can challenge me,
you can argue with me, whatever you want.
I'm here for it. Now,
usually at these events,
I show people three photos
to help them feel a bit better.
First things first would be
the image here of where I used to stand in
front of
a sheet of paper on the wall with a DSLR
camera.
I used to be in my underwear,
and I used to just shoot content there.
So although right now I'm on this nice
setup, just understand there
was a time that
I was in my budgie smugglers, and I
was just going live,
recording content, scribbling on the wall,
and it was fine.
It helped grow my business. The second
is of a graph
where I can't help
but stress this to people,
but for many years,
absolutely nothing happened within my
business.
So
2014, 2015, 2016, there was no
growth.
If you'd met me back in the day
and you'd sat next to me in
Waitrose and you'd said, "Hey, mate, what
are you doing?" I'd say, "Yeah,
I post on social media every single day."
"Oh, you
got any clients from it?" "No."
"Has it benefited your business?" "No."
You would have thought I was mental for so
long,
and it took me three years of posting
every day on social media for things
to, quote-unquote, take off.
And the very last one
is just showing you my
Instagram when it had 14,000 followers.
Don't know if the autofocus
is going to get that.
But there was a time that just like you,
I had a small account, and
when I got to 14,000,
I thought I'd made it.
I was like, oh my God, this is god tier.
How am I going to move in the street
without people going, "Oh, there's that
personal trainer from Fitness First"?
So straight off the bat,
you don't need to have a big account.
You don't need to have
any crazy following,
crazy technical setup, any of
those things.
You just need to have a good attitude.
Now, I've been on these webinars,
I've been to the business events.
I know what it's like to sit there
and learn, and I'll be honest,
a few things
we're going to talk about,
you already know.
But you need to be reminded sometimes more
than you need to be taught.
I even have that at this level where I go
back and watch old things that I've
learned,
and when I listen to something that's
said, even
years after learning it,
something can click.
So the first thing we're going to look at,
personal brand, to me, is
where information meets personality.
Now,
that's a pretty basic thing to say.
With content, some of us
are kind of a bit caught up.
Do we need to be some persona online,
or do we need to give people information?
So I want you to think about a spectrum,
not a spectrum like me with ADHD and Chris
with autism, a spectrum that,
let's say we've got brand on one side
and we've got
information on the other. Now,
the information side of things,
we need to give people what they need to
know, and that's often going to be in the
form of problem-solving. So
if you're a mortgage broker, you
are solving
the problem of helping people understand
interest rates, understanding whether or
not they should pay off their mortgage
early, helping them with the problem that
they have wondering what
is an affordable house,
helping them with all of those
things. As a personal trainer,
your clients have all got problems,
physios,
problems, et cetera. There
is information that solves problems.
It is your job to give them
that information.
Now,
sometimes we can get caught up with this
theory that we need to be so much
more intelligent or ahead of the people
that we work
with, and I disagree. So for instance,
I only think you need to be 25%
smarter than the people
that you work with.
And the reason that I say this is,
think about this video
that you're on right now.
There are people
that know way more about brand
and business than me.
Take into a case in point,
Daniel Priestley, Dan Martell,
Alex Hormozi.
But the problem is they
are too much smarter.
So imagine this. Alex Hormozi,
hundreds of millions, Dan
Martell, hundreds of millions,
Daniel Priestley, hundreds of millions.
Because they're so far ahead,
sometimes it's actually more difficult to
learn
from them than someone in my own space.
So even though I'm not multi, quad,
centi-millionaire or anything like that,
I'm actually only a few years ahead of
you. So actually,
me being a bit closer to you
is going to help me teach you stuff
because I'm not that much smarter.
Same way that in jujitsu, for instance,
when I was a white belt and a blue belt, I
would learn more from a purple belt than I
would a black belt because a black belt
has already mastered so much of jujitsu
that they actually struggle to understand
white belt problems.
They actually struggle to be in the shoes
of someone that
they haven't been for 10 years.
That could be the same reason
that you might not
vibe with Hormozi, Martell, Priestley,
whatever.
Because they haven't been in your shoes
for such a long period of time, they're
actually better off helping millionaires,
and then the millionaires would be better
off helping people
that have just started a business.
So don't think you need to be miles ahead
of people because actually, the further
you get ahead of people,
the harder you're going to relate to their
problems
because it's been so long since you've had
those problems.
So don't think you need a PhD. Actually,
in fact, where I
see the people try
and become too smart in a field,
they alienate their audience
because their audience just can't relate
to it.
Now,
some of you are going to be stuck in a
roadblock of thinking
all the information that people need
is online. Correct.
But that is just something you've made up
in your head because for years I've been
posting on social media content,
put things out.
Sometimes I'll repost something
or I'll rehash an old video
that did well And
there'll just need to be one comment of
someone that says,
"Followed you for years.
Thought I understood this.
This video just made it so much easier to
understand." Those little nuggets
are what you're searching for.
You're not looking to show so many people
that something is true for the first
time. You are trying to take
that information available on the internet
and make it
understandable for people. If I'm honest,
back in the day, I used to walk back
from Fitness First
when I finished my session,
with my little wired headphones, and
I'd put on an evidence-based podcast about
a subject, whether it was
caffeine, whether it
was about blood flow restriction training,
and I would sit
through an hour of bullshit to get home
and talk about it for three minutes.
In my head, it was about condensing
that information online and making it
better.
I would listen to a Ben Kumar podcast
that was three hours.
There was only three good points on it.
So I'd come home, make a podcast.
I studied MNU under Martin MacDonald.
The motherfucker was from a university
background where he would talk
about-- At uni,
you get an hour for a lecture.
So if you've got a topic that's 10
minutes, they drag it over an hour.
So I would listen to these modules
that were an hour long.
I would finish it and go,
"You could explain
that in three minutes." And then I was
like, "All right.
Go on." So sometimes it's about taking
that information that's
already there, making it more interesting,
and condensing it.
For me as well, when I looked around,
we had Mark Coles, Ben Kumar, Jay
Alderton, all of these people,
and I thought to myself,
"I'm never going to be
smarter.
I'm never going to be more shredded.
I'm never going to be in better shape.
But fuck me,
I could make this more interesting." So
sometimes you
don't--
Because to get smarter than someone's
going to take years.
To get better than someone's going to take
years.
To get more interesting
or to get it across in a way
that people can understand,
you can do that in a few months.
There's going to be something
that I call the
aha moment, where you do a bit of content,
or you see a bit of content,
and you have this aha moment.
So for instance, Ben Yanes,
this guy from New York,
he's got a content account.
I've been a PT for what? Over 10 years.
And he did a video the other week
explaining why is it on some pulleys,
you can go to a half stack
and do tricep extensions fine.
You can do tricep extensions,
not a problem.
But then you go to another rack,
and you go halfway down it,
you can't even move.
And he broke down
that there's a pulley system in there,
that you have single
pulleys, double pulleys, triple pulleys,
and actually you divide the weight by the
amount. I never knew that.
I just thought different mechanical
systems,
whatever. In that moment, watching
that Ben Yanes bit of content,
aha, my mind was blown. I was like,
"Oh my God.
That's insane." So there
was another one I watched back in the day
that said
that a Romanian deadlift didn't have to
touch the floor. That's your aha moment.
With your content, you
are trying to say to people, bang,
"I never even thought
that before." Another thing
that you tell people in content now
is not to leave
your call to action to the end of a video.
For instance, we're only eight minutes in,
and you might notice that in the link in
the description, there's an offer,
which is actually so flipping outrageous,
I'm
actually a little bit pissed off about it.
Because I'll give you 30 seconds of this.
My business mentorship is me.
I've got a guy called Cam helping me in
the Discord, but the other fuckers behind
the scenes, they're like, "Yeah,
discount it." I'm like,
"You ain't got to do the
work,
brother." So they keep giving me all these
codes, and that is a lower price
than I agreed to.
So there's another aha moment.
If we look at a retention graph,
even of this live,
most people would have left by
the end because I'll just be here ranting
about stuff.
So get your call to actions in more
frequently.
So we have the aha moment,
but we cannot get that
conflated with the dinner table genius.
This is another concept.
I've trademarked it.
Don't even think about trying to steal it.
Aha moment is where someone goes, "Oh,
never thought of that before.
Quite smart." The dinner table genius
is where you are going to have an
opportunity to educate someone on
something that people think is wrong,
and at
dinner table, one day,
they're going to kick off.
So Coke Zero was a fantastic one.
And for a start, if you think
Pepsi Max is better than Coke Zero,
don't take that offer because we're not
going
to get on.
We are not closely aligned as you may
think we are.
So you could say, right,
you see Menno Henselmans' post, or you
watch one of my videos,
or you read my book, whatever. Which one?
The number one bestseller. Which one? Oh,
you've got me.
So Menno Henselmans said that
if we look at aspartame
inside Coke Zero,
it's broken down into aspartic acid,
phenylalanine,
and methanol. God,
look at the memory on the kid.
That's the autism.
So you break down those things into that,
and then you say, if you were a
rat, maybe you should be worried about it.
If not,
you might have to consume over 100 cans a
day.
Now, that's cool,
and it's good to have
that amount of information.
However, the time it gets magical is
when you're sat at the dinner table,
and someone's aunt goes, "Oh,
you know that Coke Zero can give
you cancer." And you're like,
you've been waiting for this moment.
You're like, "Is that your aunt, is it?
She's about to fucking get it." Not like
that.
"Oi, shut up." You give her the facts.
You go, "Listen, Trish,
did you actually know it's broken down
into phenylalanine,
ethanol," methanol, not ethanol,
"and broken into aspartic acid.
There's more of that in tomato juice.
There's more than
that in a bit of red meat,
and there's more than that in a
fucking couple of fried eggs.
So how about you shut your mouth,
you slag?"
Now,
that is where you get to be the dinner
table genius.
And if anyone wants to
dispute that with you, that's fine.
So the dinner table genius
is about educating people.
It's giving them the understanding
and the knowledge
that should you get challenged
at the dinner table or anywhere else,
you can give them the information to not
just
have them know it,
but have them flip it on its head
and shut Trish the hell
up. So when I say it's not always
groundbreaking stuff, we
are trying to arm people with knowledge
because the second
you tell Trish to shut the fuck up,
she's going to go, "That guy online that I
learned it from,
what a legend." So content isn't just
about
educating. It's not just about reminding.
It's about arming people with the
information that they need.
The next thing to think about is, oh,
but that video has been done before.
We had a guy in my mentorship called
Michael Doherty, and
I'm not going to lie to you,
his content was going a bit stagnant for a
week.
He wasn't getting the views he wanted.
So I gave him the little,
you know in "Batman" at the end,
where they get the little nod.
I said, "Mate,
do the Coke Zero video." Now,
he didn't just do the Coke Zero
video. He did it better than anyone else.
He did it with visual props and cues,
and he used Post-it notes,
and he smashed it.
He absolutely smashed it.
He got himself, I think,
50,000 followers from that reel alone.
And since then,
that's given him not just the confidence,
but it's given him aura
Now,
you don't need permission to copy people's
stuff.
Everything you see here is copied.
This setup in here
is copied from Chris Williamson's pod
setup.
Got the headlight in the same place,
got the same camera.
I stole this mic from seeing it on another
pod.
We are taking inspiration from other
people.
We call it standing on the shoulders of
giants, but actually, we're calling it,
"That fucking worked.
I'm going to do it."
If you look at Formula 1 over the years,
one team implements something
and it works, all the other teams copy it.
This is how life works. So
when you see something that's working
well,
don't just do it, do it better.
Do you think Nutonic was the world's
first productivity drink?
Of course, it wasn't.
But we're going to do it better.
Black Friday, 21% off.
Okay,
so that's the segment we've got for
information on one side.
Information, information, information.
But now we need brand.
Where the hell is the brand going to come
into that?
So first of all,
you're going to have your approach
and your similarities.
So there are going to be some things
you're similar to other people, but your
approach might be different. For instance,
I swear to God, when I was personal
training people, sometimes I'd say,
"Put the fucking weight down,
come with me." We
used to have a whiteboard in the PT room,
and I would map things out,
carbohydrates, proteins, fats. So
when I got to content,
I very much just flipped
the exact same thing that I
was doing with clients on its head.
Now,
I would be humorous with my clients in
person, so I took
that online.
I wasn't trying to be something
that I wasn't.
Now, we all have idiosyncrasies
which make us unique
to ourselves. For instance,
Sean Casey has the personality of two
thick planks of wood, but it works.
Adam Sullivan is a Eshay chav, but it
works. Now, Adam Sullivan isn't trying,
Cunnies,
he's not trying to be something
that he's not.
He's actually trying to just be himself,
and it's working.
It's given him a cult-based audience.
Sean Casey isn't just trying to be dry
and have no personality, he's just being
himself. So because of that,
you must stick in the lane
you are and not try and be someone else,
because people will
figure it out.
And we all have an educational style.
We all have something.
For me, it's high energy,
loads of caffeine.
As you can see,
already had two coffees before I got here
this morning,
and it's about bringing the energy to the
person, because a lot of you actually
just need to be G'd up.
When I do these events in person,
people don't leave going,
"Oh my God, I learned so many..." Some do,
but most people go, "Fucking hell, I'm
getting started on YouTube."
And that's part of my brand.
It's not part of the information,
it's part of my brand.
We then have things like personal life.
Do you have a family? Do you have kids?
Do you train jujitsu? What struggles
are you going through?
We'll get into email marketing in a bit.
But having things as part of your brand.
Where I did an email the other day about
the fact that I give my kid nappy-free
time before he has a bath,
and he decided to shit on the floor,
and he was playing
with the shit.
I had to pick up my shitty son,
run to the bath, get him in the
bath, give him a wash down.
Then my missus comes down and says to me,
"Did
you clean up the poo?" My dog ate it,
right? Email, boom.
So I'm using things from my personal life
as part of my brand, and we can get into
more of that.
The relatability aspect of that
is pretty huge as well, because if
people can relate to that and go,
"Oh my God.
That's the exact type of thing my dog
or my son would do," you're going to bring
yourselves closer.
And having those things in common are key,
and I'll explain why.
You may not have ever realized this,
but let's say you drive a Volkswagen Golf.
You are more likely to let Volkswagen
Golfs out at junctions because you
feel connected to them because of
similarity.
Have you ever noticed that
when you go on holiday,
you're in Tenerife, or maybe some of you,
I don't know, Benidorm, knowing what
you're like. But you're in Tenerife,
you're next to someone on the beach, the
accent sounds a bit familiar. You go,
"Where are you from?" They go, "Oh, we're
from Berkshire." [gasps] "Mum, Mum,
they're from
Berkshire as well." "Where from?"
"Windsor." [gasps] Suddenly,
you're best mates. You're like,
"Come here, move
that sun lounge a bit closer.
Trish, you need some..."
Because you're from the same place.
When you have things
and similarities to other people,
you're automatically
already friends. Like me,
Porsche Nine Eleven, see another
guy, give him the little nod.
Similarities are massive.
So in your personal brand, this
is information, this is brand,
you can get things
over about yourself
and people can relate to it,
you're going to
do well. I was the first person that
was like, I started
calling people the C word on...
Why am I calling it?
Started calling people cunts.
Calling people cunts. Most people,
" [gasps] " But some
people are like, "Oh my God, I love
that word." Cool.
Relatability, similarity, brand.
And this helps people trust you,
because if you're showing those vulnerable
parts of your life,
if you're showing the issues
and the problems that you're
having, that helps build trust,
and we're going to get into
that a bit more.
But the considerations we need to
understand here is,
if you give people just too
much information, you're ChatGPT,
and we don't need that.
And if you're too much brand,
you're just a vlog. And again,
we don't need that.
Now, a big misinterpretation
is some people go, "Oh, but Molly-Mae
does vlogs." But Molly-Mae actually solves
a problem with her
vlogs because I've seen them on my
YouTube.
You think she's just talking about
herself,
but she's actually in the education,
not lifestyle education,
but really she's solving a problem of
girls that aspire to be her being bored
or curious about what she's
doing after a TV debacle.
If you start doing vlogs online,
as we're going to get into,
no one really cares.
Because my brand personal golden rule
is this,
nobody cares about you.
And we can say no one cares about you yet,
but I just want
you to think about this. Some of you,
nearly 1,000 of you, are going to be sat
there at home, and you might be going,
"James Smith, legend." But you're
wrong, and I'll explain why.
Because some of you might have followed me
for a few
weeks, maybe a month,
maybe a couple of years,
maybe even 10 years.
Now, in that time, if we could go back
and dissect it and
take out every single time I made you
laugh, every single time I educated you,
every single time I made something very
clear for you to understand.
If I was to take all those things out,
and we go back to that 10 years, I'm
just a dickhead with a nice car.
Because the only reason you feel you like
me is
because I helped you.
If I'd never helped you in those fields,
you wouldn't like
me. Therefore,
if you want people to care about your
brand,
and you want people to care about you,
and you want people to give you a
fist bump in a shopping center,
whatever it is, you need to help them by
solving their problems. And if you can,
make it
Fun at the same time. Again,
we're not going to get into it just yet,
but on
YouTube, people are seeking entertainment.
They're not seeking education.
They want entertainment.
Although TED Talks do well,
loads of videos do
better.
So if people want entertainment
and education, and you combine it
together, you're going to do really well.
Bit like Matt Armstrong,
which we'll talk about in a bit.
So for us to fully understand that,
let's just look at human behavior for a
second. People are self-centered, and
that is okay.
Your clients don't care about you,
they care about themselves.
Even you right now don't care about me,
you care about yourselves,
and that's cool.
When I promote the Black Friday offer,
which is link in the description, which is
an outrageous discount,
I don't want you to buy that,
so I get the money.
I want you to buy it, so it helps you.
And with that price point, trust me,
it's going to help you more than it
fucking
helps me.
And
the more we can understand about how
selfish people are,
the better you can sell to them.
Even if we think about people
that give to charity, people go, "Yeah,
but my mate
Dave, he's philanthropic.
He gives to charity." Yeah,
do you know why Dave does
that? Because it makes him feel good.
Yeah?
And when they host their little event
and everyone stands up and goes,
"Oh, Dave,
thank you for the donation last year."
Dave's there,
"Ugh," for the amount of steaks he's
getting.
That's why people don't do anonymous
donations.
Even if you go on JustFundMe
or whatever it's called,
people are there. "Yes, 10 grand.
Enjoy it."
Put the name in.
People give to charity because it makes
them feel good.
The only reason you do it,
"I paid off my mate's credit card debt." I
couldn't give
a fuck about him.
I just wanted to feel good.
Anything. My mates, have a grand. Why?
To help him?
I don't care. Made me feel good.
And at the end of the day,
that's ultimately how humans work.
Look at Chris Williamson, for example,
right?
Some of you watching this are thinking,
"Yeah, really like Chris." You
don't.
He asks people questions for a living.
That's it. That's all he does.
He just sits there going, "Hmm,
yes. Hmm. You know,
Socrates once said..." That's all he does.
But you feel like you like him because
he's solved your problem of education
and entertainment.
He's entertained you on your long drive
with the podcast, and
he's helped you with the problem because
you've always wanted to know what Bugsy
Malone was like in person.
At the end of the day,
he has built a massive
personal brand from asking people
questions, and you sit there thinking you
like him, and that's great. This
is part of the dance. This
is what we're doing.
You can quite literally just have someone
put some questions on an iPad and
become one of the world's most loved
figures.
It is that easy to play this game.
You just need to do it right.
If you want to help yourself in this
world, help others.
That's the only selfless thing I've got.
Now,
these steps get more important the more we
move, but I need
to set the foundations. God,
this blue Razz is getting me going.
Next thing I'm going to look at
is brand morphization, which I made up.
We need to jump the gun a little bit.
So for a lot of you out there, you
are doing something right now,
but I guarantee
it will not be this forever. Now,
you might have taken over your parents'
accountancy firm,
and you might be doing this forever,
but those of you doing
personal training, I guarantee,
in 10 years' time,
it's going to be something
different.
You're going to be running a business,
you're going to be looking after
something,
you're going to branch into something
else, which is why we need to
realize you are the brand. You
are the brand.
And I'm telling you this from experience.
If we think about brands that we know,
we don't think Virgin.
We don't think Apple.
We think Steven Bartlett, great
personal brand. Alex Hormozi,
great personal brand.
Lane Norton, great personal brand.
Ed Lawrence, great personal brand.
There's a business guy called Charlie
Morgan, Joe Wicks, Piers Morgan.
These are all personal brands.
Even Andrew Tate is a personal brand.
So whatever we are talking about,
the name is the brand.
Because I can already see through some of
the chats in the description, some
people are leading with their YouTube
channel not being them.
The business that we operate must sit
behind us, and let me use
those same examples again.
Alex Hormozi isn't school.com or
acquisition.com. He's Alex Hormozi.
Chris Williamson isn't Modern Wisdom.
Even when people watch Modern Wisdom
and they go, "Wow,
great podcast," they say,
"Mate, do you listen to
that Chris Williamson?" "Nah, mate,
this guy's got a
great podcast. You should tune into it."
It's Chris that's the brand.
Modern Wisdom is just the business.
Modern Wisdom is just paying the invoices
at the end of the day.
Piers Morgan has Piers Morgan Uncensored.
Joe Rogan has JRE.
Ed Lawrence, Thumbnail University.
So it's important that we understand
that people sit with the business behind
them.
Now,
I'm going to flex a little bit just for
about a minute, but this is
important. In 2016, if you'd said to me,
"James, in a year's time, you're going to
have a seven-figure fitness business," I
would've literally said, "Fuck off.
No chance. Not happening."
If you said you could put a bet on it,
I would have
bet a million pounds it wasn't going to
happen.
Now, in 2017, if you'd said, "Next year,
you're going to go on tour and do a UK
tour," I would've said,
"Fuck off." In 2018, if you were to say,
"In 2019, Harper
Collins is going to give you £100,000 for
a book," I would've told you to fuck off.
In 2019,
if you'd told me the next year
that you were going to book Coachella for
your mates, they
were going to cancel it because of a cold,
I would've told you to
fuck off. But in 2020,
if you'd told me in 2021, so middle of
lockdown, "Next year,
you're going to have 1,000 people attend
all of your events
on your tour," would've told you to fuck
off.
In 2021, in 2022, you'd said, "Mate,
you're going to be in a long-term
relationship," I would've told you to fuck
off.
In 2022, if you'd have told me
that the next year I'm going to be a
three-time
number one bestselling author,
wouldn't have believed you.
In 2023,
so I've already got a few things at this
point, if you were going to say, "You're
going to start a nootropics business
called Nootonic, and you're going to
sell millions of cans," I would've told
you to fuck off.
So
there are so many times in my life
that the very next year would've
been utterly unbelievable
and indescribable.
And the point I'm trying to make is this,
there's something called the end of
history illusion,
where we seem to think we're very much set
in our ways up until a
certain period of time,
but it's an illusion because we're wrong.
For instance,
if you think about the last 10 years,
think
about how much you've changed in the last
10 years.
The only way you can truly gauge how much
change is going to come in the next 10
years is to flip that on its head.
So every time I get to a point in time,
the next year Brings things
that I never thought were
possible. So I'm so glad
that I've now brought the brand to James
Smith,
because a few years ago, James Smith
was a fitness trainer, "Sunday
Times," what, said most in-demand PT,
whatever.
Now
over $20 million valuation drinks
business.
This mentorship, absolutely crushing.
Where am I going to be at next year?
I don't know. So chances
are none of you on this live stream have
any
fucking idea where you're going,
and that's why we must be prepared with
everything
I'm about to talk about. For instance,
your handle on social media.
If you can get your name, get your name.
Because if your brand name
is Fit4U Forever, and then you end up
opening a gym or a fucking fitness
business, or you go into
something else, and you've been front
and center for all those years,
it's hard to
move. I was James Smith PT.
I had to pay the guy that had James Smith.
And I'm not even joking here.
So I'm James Smith PT.
I find James Smith on Insta.
I message him. What is he?
A personal trainer.
I go, "Bro,
this ain't looking good for you."
If your name's Brad Pitt and you're
in Hollywood and you've never been in a
film before,
just give him the fucking handle, bruv.
You know what I mean? Give it up.
Then he's also from the same county as me,
so I was like, "Look, bro, you might be
straggling, riding some coattails
or whatever.
Just give me the handle."
So people ultimately, in business,
are going to pay you, not your
handle. Some of you think, oh, yeah,
Evolve You Coaching.
I'm like, how many people in the business?
Just me.
Take the fucking word founder out of your
bio then.
If you're making three grand a month,
you're not a
founder.
So we've got some things there.
I'm now going to give it over to you to
ask some
questions if you have any,
or we can move into the next part of it.
So that's the personal brand segment of
the conversation to make things easy.
And yeah, I'm just
asking. My manager here
is watching the questions to
make sure, and he's moaning about the...
I've got air con on, and Luke,
I need this air con on because we're going
to get sweaty.
All right. Mihai Ciprian 01 saying it's
not live. So you think this
is some kind of pre-recorded production.
How about you go fuck yourself,
you little small dick pecker
cockhead. How's that? We're fucking live.
All right,
we're going to move into the next part
because either there weren't
enough questions or yeah.
Okay, this bit is very, very important.
We'll get into those questions in a
second.
There obviously weren't enough,
or my manager is just sleeping or just
spending my money.
That's what he likes to do best.
Oh,
20%. Is it really? That's what I say.
Gross or rev? Still don't know.
So there's something here that's going to
depress
you, but at the same time,
it's going to make you feel so much better
about
everything that you're doing. Right.
I call this the pyramid attribution,
and you can tell I just make things up
randomly with names. That's the autism.
So I want you to imagine right in front of
us here is a big pyramid, and this
pyramid represents our audience.
In that audience,
not many people are going to buy your
shit. So let's say here's the pyramid.
90% of that pyramid will never buy your
shit.
Never will, never have.
And
only the top couple of percent will be
clients.
Now, we seem to think, oh,
I would love to have 10% of my audience do
it.
Never going to happen. I'd love 50%.
Never going to happen.
If you can get 5% of your audience to do
business with you, you
are flying, mate. You
are fucking doing pretty well.
The reality is 1% to 2% of your audience
will ever buy anything
in the next 10 years, and that's okay.
And you might think, why the hell
are we bothering with all of these
scumbags
bleath? If we just need this top 2%,
what are we doing with those 98%?
And something that no one's ever told you
is we need those people
algorithmically.
So as of this point,
let's imagine my business mentorship,
we probably sold 3,000
people into the mentorship,
but my following is 40,000 on
Instagram.
It's coming up to 50,000 on YouTube.
And there's part of me
that sometimes wakes up and goes, "Oi,
you fucking
dickheads,
the 47,000 aren't paying me money." And
that could get depressing.
That's the stadium of people that go,
"We're going to
watch your shit and never buy from you."
And that could make your heart rate go up.
But actually, imagine this.
We need the people that don't buy from us,
so that they can watch our content,
so it can be scored well enough
that the algorithm can push it out.
I'm going to explain that one more time.
All of those people
that never buy the thing we're selling,
if they watch our content to the end
and they enjoy it and they give it
a double tap, they
are sending signals to all the different
social media platforms,
and if those signals are positive,
the platform's going to go, this piece of
content isn't shit,
and it's going to push it further
and wider.
And when it goes further and wider,
it's then going to be seen by people who
potentially will buy our stuff.
We need to ride the
coattails of those 98% of people that
are never going to buy our shit.
So although you might have a niche,
pretty niche,
there is a time and a place for content,
and there is a time and a place to love
and adore and respect the people
that never buy your stuff.
And this is the principle I want to get
into your head.
I want you to be in the shops one day.
If you're in Australia in Woolies,
in Coles,
you've done something wrong in your
life, or you're in the UK,
you're in Waitrose.
You're in Waitrose, and
when someone's come up to you,
and they're going to give
you a fist bump, and they're going to go,
"Mate, love your stuff.
Completely changed the way I see
everything.
You've changed my life."
And then just before you think what an
amazing
interaction, they're going to go,
"Never bought anything
that you're selling, never
bought a thing, never come to an event,
never bought a book, but your content's
changed my life." There could have been a
time in my life that I would have had
that interaction and gone,
"Oh, they never bought from me." But now,
understanding the pyramid attribution,
I go, do you know what?
You're a fucking legend because I need
that person to do
what they're doing so
that other people can buy.
Even right now on this webinar,
if you all bought the offer in the
description, I'd
be fucked. I'd have to hire people.
I actually need 95% of you to not buy
that.
Otherwise,
I'm going to wake up tomorrow
and have a heart attack.
So
There is just as much gratitude
that you need to have for paid clients as
there is
for the people that never buy your shit.
And I don't think anyone's saying
that online.
No one is saying to you, "Hey,
the majority of people
that didn't buy your stuff
today are doing you a service,
and they are making your life easier."
And it is only through having this
attitude where you truly
respect and admire the people
that never buy your stuff
that you can build a strong
personal brand.
Because there's so many people you can
help
for free,
and let's not look over the fact
that even if you help someone for free,
if you're a personal trainer
and you're prospecting in the gym,
if you go over to
someone and you help them with something,
you don't ask for anything in return.
Let's say there's a strong,
able man in the gym.
I know they're not going to hire me as a
PT. I just know they're not.
So I go over, I go, "Hey mate,
what do you do?" "Oh,
I play rugby." I go away, I
look up some S&C stuff.
The next time I see that big guy, I go,
"Hey bro, here's a
few things that they're using in
professional rugby
that you might not have thought
about before." Then he's waiting for the
sales pitch, I leave.
He's going to go home and his missus
or his auntie or his cousin's going to go,
"I
really need to get personal training." He
goes, "Do you know what?
There's a really switched on blonde lad in
that gym.
He gave me some techniques the other day."
Great. So when these people that
are in your pyramid attribution don't buy
your
stuff, further down the line, they
are going to bring you business.
They are going to say, "Oh my God,
have you tried that guy's drinks?
They're amazing.
It's 21% off Black Friday."
There are so many ways you can think about
this.
I personally refund everyone from Nutonic
from my own Monzo account because I know
this. There's a lady called Jane,
she buys a flavor in Northumbria,
and she goes, "James,
don't like the taste." And I go, "Look,
I'm not only going to
refund you,
I'm going to offer you money to have your
fucking taste buds checked,"
but
I didn't say that. In the email, I go,
"Look, thank you so much for buying
Nutonic.
I don't need you to return the cans.
I've refunded you in full from my personal
account.
Please do me a favor
and give them to your friends."
The approach there is someone who
was a customer now isn't a customer.
If you treat them right,
they can then go away,
and they can give the case to their
friend and go, "Hey, look, not for me,
you might like them." There
is so much work
that can be done for people
that don't buy your stuff.
That's the point I'm making.
The law of reciprocity, you give,
you give, you give, people
are going to feel
compelled to come back. So some of you
are thinking, "Right, so I've got that
pyramid attribution. What
if I need to make more money?"
Yes, you can try and go from 1% to 2%,
but honestly,
grow the whole pyramid.
If you're at 5,000 followers
and you've got
1,000 on your email list,
if you go to 10,000 followers
and 2,000 on your email
list,
I can guarantee your business will nearly
double with it.
Okay,
so the next thing we're going to look at
is taking an in-person brand online.
So for the majority of you, there
is a world you can go online.
When I first became a PT,
people looked at me like,
"What do you mean you're PT
online?" It was like saying I
was an online plumber.
The first thing we need to look at
is being too niche is too
stupid, right?
So many people out there are like,
"I work with
left-handed lesbians, lose fat." What?
Or even some of you are like, "Yeah,
I work with 30 to 45-year-old
high-performing men." You're like, no,
you don't.
Because if some millionaire 24-year-old
wanted to work with you, you'd work with
him.
If Jeff Bezos wanted to work with you,
you'd work with him.
So the age thing, you're full of shit.
And what is a high-performing male?
Is a bricklayer a high-performing male?
Probably not,
but he might have more disposable income
than other people.
We can see what you're doing. Hey,
lesbians, if you're looking to lose fat,
stop
it. You're a dickhead. Again,
another problem that I have here is
that although I could rate Alex Hormozi in
a lot of ways, he's richer than me,
he's more jacked than me. Apparently,
he's on small dose of test.
Of course he is.
He's like, "Yeah, niche. You got to niche,
mate.
You got to niche." Alex Hormozi,
are you fucking mental?
You just grew your socials 300 posts a
week to millions of people.
You just sold 2.7 fucking million books to
everyone.
You're talking about niching.
Alex Hormozi is the king of anti-niching.
Alex Hormozi, if anything,
is the least niched person ever.
The guy went so mass market
that he's attracting fucking
14-year-old kids and 62-year-old fucking
people running funeral homes,
and he's going to lecture you about going
niche.
You fucking hypocrite, jacked
dickhead with an exceptional hairline.
So the niche thing is bollocks,
and all the people
spouting go niche, don't fucking niche.
For me, my mission statement
is I help small businesses make money
online using
social media. What's a small business?
I don't fucking know.
I just don't want someone to come, "Yeah,
I've got a billion-dollar tech company.
Can you help?" Obviously not.
Grow or make more money.
What's make more money?
Fucking just make more money.
You can go from 10K a month to 100K.
You can go from 1K to 2K, I don't care.
Using social media. What social media?
I don't care.
If someone reads
that mission statement and goes, "Yeah,
sweet, sounds right,
get in." But if they don't want to make
money online,
they don't want to use social
media, and they don't have a business,
they're going to read
that mission statement
and go, "It's not for me."
You know what I mean?
Another question people have is whether
or not you use social
media. You don't have to, but
if you look around right now in the world,
in
Ireland and in Dubai,
when you cross the road,
they've got the colors,
like the red light, green light,
on the fucking floor, brother.
So if you're fucking crossing the road,
they know people are like
this.
You know what I mean? People
are just like this the whole time.
So now that they put fucking green
and red lights on the floor so you don't
get hit
by traffic, take a hint. There
are signals in the market, right?
People can't even look up to save their
fucking life.
So if people are on social media
that much, don't invest in billboards,
invest in
social media. So
another consideration
is getting people's attention on social
media is the easiest
it's ever been.
It just takes one video to really change
your life.
One video pops off,
and the one video kicking off isn't always
that you get
business from that video.
Sometimes you just put in the grind,
the grind, the
grind. Then when that one video pops off,
it doesn't just give you confidence,
right? It gives people aura.
And I know aura is such a cheesy
thing to say, but
when someone's popped off and
gone viral and made a bit of money,
they walk differently.
And to me, we've got stocks, ETFs, crypto,
whatever.
The best interest savings account in the
world, for me, has been social media.
And whenever I've had a spare 10K,
I put it into camera, mic,
studio, all of these things.
Even my last book deal I've
signed I got my advance.
They paid me way too much.
I've given it half away already to my
favorite author to help me write it.
Whenever I get money, I think,
"How can I use this to make more money?"
I'm putting
it into the social media interest savings
account and writing a book because, by
doing that book, I get more content,
I get more things to talk about,
more things
to... Anyway, it comes back full circle.
If I just put that money
and put it into a fucking ETF,
cool.
It might compound over a few years
and build generational wealth.
Or I'll hire a fucking weapon that's going
to make me write a book that's 10 times
better,
and I'll get the money back in a year
or two.
So social media also
is going to help us with
that brand morphization, the fact
that we don't know where we're going.
So if we can collate people's interests
over time on social
media,
most my data was from personal training.
When we launched that book,
I didn't become a number one "Sunday
Times" bestseller
because of how good that book was.
I did it because I had an email list from
running a fitness business.
Then all the events, everything, blah,
blah, blah,
blah, blah. Do the sellout,
Hammersmith Apollo, get all of this data.
Then suddenly, when you release a drink,
you've done four million cans.
The business I built to run a fitness
empire then made selling books very
easy.
Then everything I did selling books made
launching a drinks brand
very easy.
The brand morphization of social media,
you
think 1.3,
1.4 million of my followers on Insta
came for fitness,
and they're now drinking my drink.
That's why we need to not overlook
or turn our nose up at social media.
And for most of you, it's free.
Social media is free.
You might pay 15 pound a month,
but that's free. You know what I mean?
Okay,
we need to look at some personal brands
that are crushing right now. Hmm.
Some of you may know of a guy on YouTube
called Matt Armstrong.
He pretty much rebuilds crash-damaged
cars.
But any of you that go back and watch it,
I just need you to realize he's not.
He's telling stories,
and the only thing
that changes in the stories is the car.
This guy's getting millions of views.
He's built a massive personal brand.
In the lockdown, he
was working in an Indian restaurant,
serving tables.
He's now one of the biggest YouTubers in
the world, and he's found something that
people are interested in. And again,
you know what we spoke about before.
You think you're just watching a car
channel, but you're not.
It's education and entertainment, and
when you put those things together,
you have
an irresistible channel.
When you watch content online, especially
YouTube,
and we're going to talk about YouTube a
bit because I actually think a lot
of what we're doing is going to YouTube.
You guys,
we know we spoke about watching people,
human
behavior. How many of you,
when you put the TV on,
go straight to YouTube?
Back in the day, you'd put on Netflix.
You might check what's on the TV.
Now, I can't help but feel
that a lot of us just go into YouTube.
Now,
for all of you pommy English people
that are watching, there is a channel
online called Carwow.
For all of you Aussies,
Australia's really fucking backwards,
right?
You go down the road in Australia,
they have cars on the side of the road
with
signs that say, "For sale." And I'm like,
"Mate, it's 2025, and you
thought the easiest way to sell your car
was to get an A4 bit of paper and put some
fucking writing on it with your phone
number on the street." In the UK,
there are
so many different ways. We Buy Any Car,
whatever.
Now, Carwow, for many of you,
think just does drag races.
But if you look, their YouTube's genius.
It's got over 10 million subscribers,
and they reuse the same thumbnail on every
single video, which is two cars,
usually side by side, and the question
is what
wins in a drag race between a Lamborghini
Huracán and a Porsche 911 GT3. Cool.
Because they found packaging that works,
every single video follows the same
packaging. But because the cars change
and the curiosity changes,
they have a new video they can put out.
Now, I'm not sure if you've realized this,
but Carwow uses the
exact same formula for viral content
that every single video should follow.
So if you click on a Carwow video,
what wins in a drag race between a Huracán
and a 911 GT3?
Hook. Now, just with that hook alone,
we already know what's happening in
this video.
We're going to find out what wins.
Now,
we can't leave after the hook because
if we want to know the answer, we must
stay. Right? So then, just before that,
we have, "Well, I'm
Matt Watson,
and you're watching Carwow," which
is a little bit of an introduction.
I'm not really mad on that.
But they don't go straight into the drag
race.
They go in something called a setup.
So we have the hook,
which makes people realize what I'm going
to get from the
video. The setup in Carwow is,
so the Huracán has a
naturally aspirated V10.
It's got four-wheel drive,
and the setup has actually
given us more information about the cars
so that we can start to
predict an outcome. We
are becoming more invested in it.
We are finding out which one's worth more,
which one's got all-wheel drive, which
one's rear-wheel drive,
what's the horsepower.
We're actually getting into an
anticipatory part of the video where we're
going,
"Oh, well, I didn't know
that the Huracán was four-wheel drive.
The 911's only two-wheel drive."
And we're building up to the payoff.
And as we are building up, we
are getting more emotionally invested.
You start to think, "Do you know what?
I think the Huracán's going to do this.
Huracán has got a bigger engine,
and it's also got..." You know what I
mean?
So we're going through the setup,
and as we're going through the setup,
we're
learning, remember? Education
is going to be learning about the cars.
The entertainment is watching the drag
race.
So we get there, we get there,
we get there.
Just before they do the drag race, boom,
ad read.
Because you've got someone from the hook,
you've got someone to the setup.
If they did the ad read before the setup,
people would leave.
If they did the ad read before the hook,
If they did the advert after the payoff,
people would leave.
So the only place you can put a call to
action is between the setup
and the payoff. Then you get the payoff,
which is the cars doing the drag race, and
that's in the later part of the video.
Every single piece of content should
follow this,
a hook where people know in the
first few seconds what they're watching,
what they're going to get, and whether or
not they should stay around.
It should build curiosity where they want
to get the
answer.
The setup is where you give them more
information about what
is happening.
It's where you give them context, nuance,
whatever.
Then we work up towards the payoff.
If you do the payoff too early,
people leave.
If you do the payoff too late,
There was a lad in the mentorship who,
he ate eggs on toast for a day,
and I was like, "Mate,
this isn't really a good video.
Tell you what,
do me a video where you only eat eggs on
toast for a week to
make your point." So his hook is,
"I ate only eggs on toast for a week to
lose fat." Cool. Hook.
That's a statement hook,
not a question hook,
but he said there what he was going
to do. Now, people that go, "Hmm,
could you lose fat doing that?" Or,
"Why is he
doing that?" Are going to stay around.
[clears throat] Instead of doing the
setup, he then said,
"I lost 2.3 kilograms."
And the video bombed, and I said to him,
"Mate, the reason this has bombed is
because you paid them off before the
setup." You've given them the hook, then
you've paid them off.
The next one minute of your video
is irrelevant.
In the beginning of a film,
you don't have an introduction,
then find out what the
main thing is that happened,
then just have loads afterwards.
So on YouTube, we can see this online,
it's really important.
There are so many things I need you to see
in content now that you may not have
noticed before.
Because unless you start to analyze this,
you can't make your own
content better. So let's think about this.
"Top Gear."
If you grew up with "Top Gear," best time
of my life watching that Sunday evening
before bed with the parents.
Our favorite episodes
were always the ones where they went on a
trip, when they
went to the Arctic,
or they went to the South of France
because it's a story.
It's not just journalism, it's a story.
So in your own head, you should know
that "Top Gear" is better
when they have the
stories than anything else. Then also,
the story isn't just going from here
to here. There are raising the stakes,
having the car behind
them. There are things that go wrong.
There are so many things in that.
The car breaking down,
all of these storylines in
it. We are attracted to stories.
Now,
the reason that I get excited about
YouTube is
there was a study conducted not too long
ago that said, on average people need to
get seven hours of content from you before
they buy from you.
Seven hours, let's just use that.
I'm actually not sure if that is the
exact amount of hours for whatever.
Now, Daniel Priestley has the
4-11-7 rule, where he says it's four
platforms, seven hours of content,
11 touch points,
something like that, and I agree.
So what I've done is,
I've actually done the
maths before this call.
The average Instagram Reel is one minute.
If you wanted to do one-minute videos
every day to
accumulate seven hours,
you would need to do 420 videos.
420.
And that's if people even watch one
minute.
Now, if you're posting four times a week,
that'll take you two years.
So when we're thinking about accumulating
that seven hours of content, on
short-form content especially,
could take you two years.
If you were to do five posts a week,
it would take you 1.6 years, and
if you were
only posting three times a week,
it's going to take you two
and a half years.
So for some of you out there that
are only posting reels, and you're only
putting stuff on content maybe three times
a week, you're two years away from
acquiring that seven hours. Even today,
right now,
nearly 1,000 of you have already
got 45 minutes of time from me. That
is the same as you
watching a one-minute reel every single
day for 45 days, but you wouldn't even
watch them every day.
We so far have already built maybe several
months
of rapport. You've heard me.
You know I haven't taken a break yet,
right?
And you know this is a live recording.
So this time that we're accruing now
towards that seven hours is helping you
understand whether
or not I actually know what I'm talking
about.
But now the average YouTube video
is 11 minutes.
The interesting thing
is it used to be 13 minutes,
but the average YouTube video is
getting shorter.
I know some people straight away
are going to think to themselves,
"Oh, James,
how long should a YouTube video be?" This
is your golden rule as well.
It can never be too long,
it can only be too boring.
I'll repeat that one more time.
It can only be too long.
It can never be too long,
it can only be too boring.
Matt Armstrong, the guy that repairs cars,
he takes his one-hour videos, bops
them all together,
puts them on his Mark2 channel.
Some of the videos are seven,
eight hours long.
They've got 20 million views.
Because he retention edited those videos
for so long, they do really well.
So if you were to put out 11-minute
YouTube videos and
you were to do three a week, which
is quite a lot, you would have
that person as a
client in three and a half months,
maybe three months.
Three months. So 11-minute videos,
three times a week, which would be
more work, I get it, you would get
that seven hours in three months.
If you were doing five videos a week,
you could get it in a month, maybe two
months. Now,
I'm not saying you'll need to run to
YouTube.
What I'm saying is,
so much of you for your personal brand,
you want to start off
short-form content,
you want to start on Instagram, TikTok,
Facebook, but then I
want you to think about this.
If you needed seven hours of time in front
of people,
would you do more live streams like this?
Would you do more YouTube videos?
Would you do more longer pieces of content
to get that seven hours?
Would you be acceptable waiting two years
to get someone to watch enough
content,
or would you diversify the modalities of
content that you're doing?
Would you appear on podcasts more?
Would you start your own podcast?
Whatever it is.
I didn't realize this in the beginning,
but when I was going live
back in 2016, 2017, it wasn't
that my live streams were that amazing,
it's that I was getting seven hours of
people very quickly.
When I started my podcast in 2021,
I just thought it was a popular podcast.
I thought it was good for sales. I
was getting seven hours from people,
sometimes
in a week. So we must think
that with our personal brand,
the information,
everything that we're doing,
we must use everything in our power to
ensure that we are working towards
that seven hours.
I am working towards
that seven hours right now with you,
with the link in the
description,
with the discount for the Black Friday
discount.
Now,
when it comes to growing a personal brand,
there are some other considerations
we need to take into account. Number one,
exposure, and that's just
being seen. On YouTube, we call
that impressions.
Short-form content has never been easier
with something that we call the
TikTok-ification of social media.
So ever since the pandemic,
TikTok came along.
Instead of serving us content based on who
we were following, they served it to us
on what we were interested in.
So back in my day,
people had to follow me to see my content.
Right now, you can put out a banger reel,
and the whole internet will get shown it.
So the TikTok-ification,
although more people
are now posting on social media, it's
never been an easier time. But
at the same time,
long-form content has benefits as well.
For instance,
something called the binge effect.
If you look at any of the end of my
YouTube videos, I'll often go, and
[imitates narrator]
So if I watch,
or you watch a video of 10 minutes,
and then I point to another one
that's five minutes, and you watch both,
that average view duration has gone from
10 minutes to 15 minutes.
That means YouTube and the algorithm
is going to score
that higher.
Then if you then watch another one,
watch another one, and watch another one,
the
other benefit of that is
if you've just watched a 10-minute video,
you are very
likely to finish the second video.
So there are so many kind of
easy on short-form TikTok-ification,
easy on long-form getting binge
effects.
Now, short-form content is a lot easier.
If you watch Adam Sullivan recently,
you'll notice that on Instagram,
you can quite literally just press the
plus button.
"Hi yeah, guys,
just doing a live stream today.
If you want to tune in at any point,
just comment the word live." Cool. Sweet.
Done. No production, nothing. For this,
got to put the camera on, edit,
all of those things. So short-form
is easier, but the impact is lessened.
So You need to start thinking about those
seven hours, people.
For your personal brand,
whatever you're doing right now,
we need to get to that
seven hours. Now,
when it comes to building your brand,
we also need to talk about
personal growth. So
if you play Grand Theft Auto,
you know you need to level up
your character.
You need to get doing missions,
you need to start getting
experience,
you need to start at the bottom, eat shit,
do the boring stuff.
But as you work up,
you get access to more resources. Life
is very much like that.
There are going to be professional
accolades,
but I'm not going to lie to you guys,
if you have got funky letters after your
name, unless you're a doctor,
unless you're operating on me,
or unless you're a dentist, I don't care.
So many S&C coaches try
and suck off their own S&C qualification.
No one cares.
I would rather you have personal accolades
as well.
If you're a triathlon or a HYROX person,
win some fucking
competitions. Even for jujitsu,
I'll probably be a black belt in the next
couple of years, but I'm not just the
black belt that I want to be.
I'm a brown belt that goes
and wins competitions.
I beat black belts competitions.
I compete in adult divisions. I get about.
Now, for me, I've never made a-- Actually,
I have made a bit of money from jujitsu.
I got paid $1,000 to compete once,
and I got Take Down of the Night, so
$1,500
petrol money. [chuckles] I'm only joking.
So with that,
your personal brand isn't just the
components of your
business. Jujitsu isn't my business,
but I still want to show people
grit, perseverance, audacity,
all of those things.
So growing your personal brand,
you need to also level up your character.
Now,
I'm not saying you all need to become a
black belt in jujitsu, but there
should be some level of competency there.
Because some of you from this call,
you're going to click the link in the
description,
you're going to give me a couple of grand,
right?
And with that couple of grand,
you don't just want me to be a killer in
social
media, a killer in landing pages,
content critiques, all of those things.
If I'm here and I've got the third
quickest track
time in a GT3 at the local track,
I've got my black belt in jujitsu, and I'm
three times number one bestselling author,
you're like, nah, this person strives
for excellence in every component of his
life. That's what makes a good mentor.
So if you're a coach
or you're someone in that world,
any kind of accolade that you
can get and put your name, you
are building a persona that people go,
"Do you know
what?
I want to be associated with that." Again,
Dan Martell, Daniel Priestley,
Alex Hormozi, love them,
could beat them all in a fight.
So at the end of the day, sure, there are
people with more money than me,
could they beat me in a fight?
Gordon Ramsay would, but apart from that.
And again, experience.
I'll be honest with you,
and I've said this
before,
I've actually learned half of what I know
about
business in the last 10 years
and half what I know about business in the
last 12
months. I, and you guys
are probably the same,
even as personal trainers,
the rate in which you learn experience
comes at such quicker rates.
It comes so much quicker than you can ever
really think about it.
You seem to think that, oh,
it's going to be the same amount every
year.
I'd say your ability to learn doubles
every year.
So
we spoke about that fist bump effect
before.
For the personal brand,
I want you to be happy with people
that never bought,
people that never will, people that say,
"I should have paid you," people that say,
"You helped my nan." Let's remember
that the pyramid attribution, without the
people that never buy our stuff,
we'll never get the people that will.
Let's move into questions for this segment
before we move into the next one.
So I have nearly 1,000 people on here.
It's very flattering.
Let's get into some of the questions.
Cosmin Tiliman,
"I don't really like to be a pushy
salesman.
How important is
that in online business?" Great question.
Neither do I.
And what some of you may not realize
is I'm actually quite introverted, so I
actually don't like being with people all
too much. It drains the fuck out of me.
When I do the events in person,
I'm wiped out for three, four days.
I'd like nothing better. Right now,
I'm in my studio, no one's here.
This is just me.
I don't know anyone within almost half a
mile of here. Great.
I've never done a sales call in my life.
So I'm not really keen on selling to
people either, bro.
So what I do is I create landing pages.
So when you click
that link in the description,
for instance, that takes you to a
landing page.
You don't need to have a sales call.
There's a video,
there's all the information.
Buy it, don't buy. I do the input here,
then I wake up, money in my
bank account tomorrow. That's it.
I'm not pushing people into it.
And if someone needs to be pushed, this
is what I say, "Hey,
fucking join,
and if within three months I've let you
down on any side of
this deal and I've not given you what I
promised you, email me."
Cool. With Nutonic, I've said to people,
I'm not like, "Hey, guys,
please buy Nutonic. Oh my God,
it tastes..." Actually,
I am a bit like that at the
moment, but relax. So with this, I say,
look, any of you watching this, if you go
to our Black Friday discount, 21% off,
I won't even ask for confirmation.
If you don't like it, drop me an email,
james@nutonic.com.
I'll refund you in full.
So I like using a guarantee instead of
being a salesperson.
I like to put your mind at ease.
That's probably the best form of sales
that you could have.
Rule the Trainer,
"How many emails time would you say it
takes on average for a new
email subscriber to buy an offer service?"
It depends, which is I know a bit of a
cop-out question,
but how did you get the leads?
So if you've just blown up on social
media,
they've just joined your email list,
that could take time. Also, how good
are the quality of the leads?
If they came from TikTok,
they're going to have a much different buy
rate than
coming from Instagram.
And how long it takes them to buy an offer
depends on how
good the offer is,
how well-curated your landing page is.
Because at the end of the day,
if you've got a shitty landing page,
that could be
strangling the bottleneck of your
business.
So some of you have got amazing socials,
amazing email marketing, amazing
lead magnet,
then you get to your landing page
and you're hosting it on fucking
Wapp or School,
and it looks like dog shit.
The font is too small,
and the buttons don't work, or whatever.
So there are so many different components.
Instead of you saying how many emails
or time does it take, I would say,
where is
the bottleneck in your business,
and let's address it.
Because this is why you need to use
landing pages.
And by the way,
we're going to get into landing page
versus website.
Your sales page must give you data on
visits and conversions.
The reason is, if you go, "James,
I'm not converting any sales," I'd say,
cool.
Is it a traffic problem,
AKA we're getting good conversion rates,
4% or
5%, but not enough people joining, or
are we getting loads of people visit our
site
and no one's buying? Those two things
are very different remedies.
Martine Matapo,
"How to decide what type of business
or products I should start
with?"
Okay,
this is the first thing you need to know.
Sometimes I go on people's socials and go,
"What are you selling?" So you need to
really find out what it
is you're good at
and what problems you can solve.
Don't post on content.
Don't start any of this till you
are sure about what you're
selling.
"Dave,
how do you compete with other PTs in a
corporate gym like Fitness First, for
example?" You just talk to people.
It's the only way you've got out of it.
Ask Fitness First if they'll send an email
to the members introducing you, but you
just got to talk to people.
I got someone try
and fight me on my first day because
I was trying to talk to them.
Another thing you can do
is build up your social
media. What I love is,
and there's definitely an ego component
here, for my
first month at Fitness First, I
was going up to people and begging them,
"Hey,
do you want to do a free session?" They
told me to fuck off.
I'd go over and try and give people, like,
"Oh, hey, mate, can I give you
a little bit of a tip?" And they
were like, "No." Mate,
I just got shushed away by
so many people when I
was a personal trainer at Fitness First.
So many people just didn't care.
And then as I grew my
socials and my following started getting
bigger, 40, 50K, 60K, the same
people that told me pretty much to fuck
off or took their headphones out and were
like, "No, thanks," then started going,
"Oh, James, can I book in a session?" And
I'd be like, "No, fuck you guys.
I hate you." But don't tell them to fuck
off.
So also, if you want to compete, one,
you have to prospect, but two,
sometimes you
just need to level up your character,
because if you get to a certain level of
status and notoriety within the community,
those clients are going to come to you.
And again,
remember what I said about being an
introvert.
I take it very personally
when people say no to me.
It's one of the reasons I don't do sales
calls.
If you don't want to buy my shit,
I don't want to know about it, I don't.
I don't want to sit on a sales call
and beg you to join my shit for you to go,
"I'll have to think about it." That'll
ruin my day.
Instead, I want no feedback, brother.
I don't want any rejections.
I've had enough of
that in my life from door-to-door sales.
Level up your character
and they'll come to you.
LukeJuju15, "You show up daily on email,
LinkedIn, how do you never miss a day
without running out of things to talk
about?" You get creative,
and being creative
is just like a muscle, bro.
Like the same way
that you can train a muscle, you can
train the creative part of your brain.
You and I started in the same position.
I used to have zero followers.
We all started with zero followers on our
social media account.
And because I show up-- You say,
"How do you show up daily
and stay creative?" I
go, "If you show up daily,
you can stay creative."
Tika, wow, that's a complicated name.
"If I've already made videos about solving
my clients' problems, how can I move
through the plateau
and find new content ideas?" Motherfucker,
I've been doing
the same 10, 15 videos over
and over again for 10
years, bro. It's not about new,
it's about making it better.
Imagine this,
if I go to your social media profile right
now, and I say, I get a
fucking gun out, and I go,
"Show me the best fucking video you've
ever done." And
you go, "It's this one." I go,
"Not just views.
Which one got you the most fucking
clients?" You go, "Oh, it
was this one." I go,
"Cool. Can you make it better?
If you don't make it better,
I'm going to kill your
whole fucking family." And you're like,
"Oh, yeah, I can make-" Well, go and make
it better then. Because if
that video got you 10 fucking clients
before,
if you make it a better version of it,
you might get 15.
And then you go, "Okay, now what?" Well,
let's find the second-best video you've
ever done and make it better.
All you ever do is just keep redoing them.
If you go to my YouTube,
most of them, or even my Instagram,
it's the same fucking videos over and over
again. Think about this. Imagine you see a
skyline. There's a big building in there.
You go,
"I'm going to build a bigger one." So you
build a bigger one.
Someone's going to come along and go,
"Do you know what we're going to do?" Go
on.
"Build a bigger one." They build a fucking
bigger one.
Then some other cunts come along,
and they go,
"We should build a bigger one than
them two." Build the next one.
Now all of these people out-competing each
other,
the Burj Khalifa will no longer be the
tallest building in the world within
probably 10, 15, 20 years, whatever.
You just have to keep skyscraping all of
your own videos.
So you don't just make a video on
everything, then move on because you are
accelerating and learning at such a
different rate.
Your creativity over time compounds way
bigger than an ETF.
How can I find new content ideas?
Go back and make them fucking better, bro.
Dan Devinside,
you said you're from Windsor, I saw that.
"Thoughts on high-ticket sales.
I've always been told by others to sell
high
ticket, and to be honest,
I always thought it was ludicrous.
Would rather sell affordable coaching."
Okay.
I know exactly who your fucking business
mentors are from this. Okay.
Now,
I'm just going to tell you a little bit of
a truth about the industry.
So I hate high ticket, I hate low ticket,
I hate the terminology, it's bollocks.
There are coaches out there
that want you to charge big amounts for
long
amounts of revenue,
and the reason they want to do that
is so you can have a big
month.
And the reason they want you to have a big
month is they can market you.
So let's say you're making two to three
grand a month.
You go join one of these gurus,
and they go, "Don't focus on anything
apart from high ticket. High ticket.
You're going to charge three grand for
three months." And they big you up,
they go,
"You're worth it, brother.
You're worth it."
And then they're going to get on
high-pressure sales calls.
You're not going to mention pricing,
right?
Starting to sound familiar.
So you then start getting all your leads,
and you find
your 5, 10 highest leads.
Now you put them all into your diary for a
week, and you
go on there and you close,
and you have your strategies
and your sales systems.
Now you sign four people at three grand,
you made 12 grand in a month.
Now,
although you've just taken half a year's
revenue and compressed it all the way
into where you are right now,
that guru doesn't give a shit about your
business.
They just want to go, "Hey, Dan. Dan,
how much were you making before?"
"Three grand." "What'd you make last
month?" "12." "Sign up to me mentorship.
Sign up. I took Dan.
He's making 10K a month now.
He's making 10K." They're only doing it
for the vanity of the metrics
of how it looks for them.
Now, there is no high ticket,
and we're going to get into
that into the next thing.
You charge based on demand.
When loads of people want your shit,
you can charge more.
My business mentorship
was $999 a year ago.
What happened? More people want it. Why?
Because I turned up and built my socials,
built my brand, built the reason that you
should believe me,
and now I get to charge more.
One more question.
Again, NemaTheMachine,
"As a small creator, high ticket
or low ticket to start
with?" How about you charge what you're
fucking worth?
And what I mean by that is,
once you are full,
we're going to get into this,
you increase your prices.
And if you're not full,
you're not marketing hard enough.
Okay, one more. DomiSwee64 or 84,
"For someone starting out, what's
your thoughts on warm outreach?
Messaging people
that follow on social media?"
Absolutely fucking not.
A load of business gurus decided wanking
off each other,
being like, "Oh my God,
there's a mini chat feature where you can
DM people that
follow you." I actually followed a guy the
other day who's a millionaire of cars,
and I got an auto response, and I
was like,
"You fucking desperate cunt." Listen,
you should not be messaging people.
Because they follow you, they
are not warm.
I just fucking told you
that 98% of people will never fucking buy
your shit.
You are on the cusp of making
that 99 to 100 with this beggy fucking
outreach bollocks. Now, when people
are ready, they will come to
you. That is how we build these brands.
No DMing strangers.
Now, you can DM them
if they comment on your post a certain
word that you've put in
there as a money chat automation,
but you do not want to scream desperate.
Imagine this.
I've got a few hundred K kicking about at
the moment,
right?
And I'm not sure where to invest it.
So my friend's been buying property in
Victoria, and I was like, "Oh,
sweet." They
go,
"I'll connect you." This motherfucker
called me three times in a day.
I was like, "No,
I'm never buying any property off this
fucker." Because he was
so desperate, sending me emails,
all of that.
Now,
if this guy had ignored me for three
weeks, I'd go, "Let's buy some fucking
property." But because he
was so desperate and so clingy
and so in my face
trying to get business,
he's completely turned me off.
I will never buy anything from this person
ever.
Again,
let's say you meet a girl at a bar
and she texts you too much, or you meet a
guy and he texts you too much.
You're like,
"This person's a fucking psycho." Now,
if you follow someone
and automatically hit a DM, it
is desperate.
And again,
every single one of you knows this in the
dating market.
If you get a sniff of desperation,
you go nowhere near someone,
nowhere near them.
Whether it's a dude at 35 being like,
"Please go on a date with me."
Or it might be
a woman at 33 going,
"Should we get another drink tomorrow
night?" They've always
got the crazy eyes.
Do not get too desperate.
Okay,
we're going to move into the next segment.
We're going to get through some more of
the questions at the end.
Okay,
so one thing we need to understand
is avatars.
Avatars are the people
that we're communicating to on social
media.
Because although we have
that pyramid attribution,
we don't want to talk to
everyone.
So we all need a basic mission statement.
And so many of you do not have this. I go,
"Who do you work with?"
And they go,
"I help people overcome stress
and build self-confidence
whilst living a life of being truly free."
I'm like, "What the fuck is that?
It's not a mission statement." There
should be maybe two to three things you
help
people with, and they can't be bland.
I help people lose fat
and build muscle and get fit.
Oh, so you just fucking help everyone,
do you?
Whatever it is, make it clear.
Make it something you can say in one
breath.
The choice of language, mission statement,
choice of language. Do you swear?
How do you talk? How's your cadence?
I'm quite in people's faces.
That's just how it is. Your avatar,
you must speak to a specific problem as
well.
So often I will talk about landing pages,
I will talk about contacts, I'll talk
about data.
I'll talk about all of these things
because I know your problems.
There must be relatability to your
avatars.
Now,
there's also something you might not
notice when you watch adverts on
TV. Even the voice they use
is perfect for the client.
So a Range Rover advert is,
"Head into your local Range Rover
dealership
to see what we can do on the new Vogue."
But then if you see a Toyota Hilux,
it's like,
"Get down to Toyota with a seven-year
warranty on the new
Hilux." They even talk in the voice of the
person they want to attract.
Now, if any of you are unsure,
you should all have a perfect favorite
client.
Mine, her name was Susan Green.
Susan Green, Jackie Smith,
they're my two favorite
clients of all times.
Every time in fitness when I turned up
and spoke about that, so many times
when I spoke about anything, I was
talking to Jackie and Susan because
if you have a perfect client,
you want more
people like that.
Susan Green used to bring me leftovers
from a dinner that I
could have for lunch.
I wanted more clients like that.
So,
when you've got your avatar,
think of your choice of language.
If you swear or not,
it's going to determine how many of those
people are going to
be drawn towards you.
I made the mistake of wearing a polo shirt
and having an iPad.
I tried to be professional as a PT,
and guess what?
I attracted fucking loads of bellends.
I did.
I attracted so many bellends who would
come in and be like, "Oh, James, yeah,
finance bro," blah, blah, blah. But now,
I even
wear vests and shorts
when I do speaking gigs. Why?
Because they're the type of people I want
to attract.
Do you want to know my level of
professionalism?
I ain't even wearing shoes, brother.
I don't even wear shoes anymore.
I don't wear them to go to the shop
because I don't care.
And if someone goes, "Hey,
that James Smith is a bit of a scruff."
Oh, who cares?
Brand.
Now,
we're going to talk about something you
might not have been expecting, right?
Financial goals and materialistic
obsessions.
I think all of you,
although you should be focused on your
business, should have
something in mind like a luxury car
that you want.
I actually think materialistic obsessions
are good.
I think that you should want to fly
business class with your partner.
Gerald Lee at the weekend flew from
Singapore.
I did a bit of one work with him last
year.
I see him on his Instagram flying business
class.
When he turns up to the event
that we did last weekend, I said to him,
"Hey, mate,
how was business class?"
And that's his first flight.
Not only did he fly business,
he surprised his missus.
So his missus was getting to the airport,
had no
idea.
There are so many things in your life,
in your world that can change,
right? I will never forget
when I took Tay flying back
from the UK to
Sydney, and when we got on the plane,
she hadn't noticed her ticket said first
class.
So we'd flown business a couple of times.
She hadn't noticed.
And so when you get on Emirates,
when you're business class, they go,
"Yeah, down
there on the left."
When you go first class, they go,
"Come with me," and they take
you to your apartment.
Tay cried. She was that overwhelmed.
She couldn't believe it.
She was like, "Oh my God." We get there.
She's crying.
She's having a glass of champagne.
That moment to me meant more than all the
money I'd made all year.
The time that I drove out a Porsche
dealership, and not even my dream car.
My dream car was an Audi RS6, right?
My lifetime dream car,
I only had it for 10 months,
and then I sold it and got
something better. So
it's good to have these things you want to
do.
It's not a waste of money to have a
magical moment because when I die,
I'll probably have a flash of all the
things that were important to me.
It'll probably be any children that I had,
the time I flew first class with my
missus.
Even my son at four months old got to fly
first class,
which don't do, by the way.
Business class is better with kids.
Just throwing it out there.
You get the bar at the back.
In first class,
you don't even have a cubbyhole to put the
pram in, so it has to go
at the end. But anyway,
we'll get into that.
So you should have ambitions.
Maybe the car's a two, three-year goal.
But all of you within the next year,
your business should pay for a business
class
flight. And it doesn't matter
if it's only to Europe
or it's to New York or
whatever. It's so, so amazing.
You'll have so many hard days at
work,
but when you see your kid asleep in
business class, it's honestly worth
everything Okay,
so we're going to get into the sales
process, arguably one of the
most important parts of this entire video.
So sales calls is one of the things
that I butt heads on with a lot of people.
I'm going to say this, sales calls work,
but if it's the only thing you've ever
done, of course it works.
Think about this.
So let's say some dude walks into the gym,
he's got a really good chest, and all he
does is press-ups.
Imagine I say to him, "Oh, mate,
you could do cable flies
and bench press." He's
going to go, "No,
just do press-ups." He has
that vision of the world because it's
all he's ever done. Right?
And a lot of these mentors
that some of you have used
before, of course, they like sales calls.
Do you know why?
Because they are fucking shit at email
marketing.
They've got the personality of a fucking
plank, and they have no design concepts
for making a good landing page.
And because imagine this,
I'm just going to throw
this out there.
My job would be so much easier
if I got all of
the people in my mentorship to just
fucking do sales calls.
"Hey, just get on a call,
tell them why it's good,
give them a guarantee." But I
don't want to give them the things
that I don't want to do.
So sales calls work,
but they often work because they're the
only fucking thing
that you're doing.
Now,
there is something called the empty diary
effect.
So if I get on your diary and there
are loads of
fucking call slots available,
it's like walking past an empty
restaurant.
Let's say you're in Majorca,
you're on a family holiday,
you're walking down a
cobbled street,
and you see a restaurant that's completely
fucking empty. Right?
"Hey, come in, we got great food." No,
you fucking don't, mate.
I can't even see a fucking chef.
There's no one in there.
Food poisoning and diarrhea.
That's what you think when you see empty.
So if you showcase someone an empty diary,
bounce, they're gone.
And again, not many of you
are getting the data from Calendly of the
amount of
people that went to book a call
and then fucked off.
So then some of you go to the scarcity
effect, and you only open two slots a day.
Now, if I get to your diary
and the only two slots a day
are at 3:00 a.m.
and 4:00 a.m., I fucking bounce.
If it's at 4:00 p.m.
and I'm at work, I'm bouncing.
If it's at midday,
that's my fucking lunch break,
I'm bouncing. So many of you,
whether you look to scarce or you look to
open,
you're fucking yourself through the empty
diary effect.
Then you've got time wasters,
and the time wasters are the people
that sit through
the whole fucking call and go, "Yeah,
just going to talk to my
husband." That hour of your time is gone,
and it's
not just the hour, right?
Because you have the hour
that you spent on the call, but
if you're like me, you stress.
If something's in my diary at 3:00 p.m.,
I can't
relax until I've done the 3:00 p.m.
So there's the hour before the call where
you're making sure there's an alarm you
set on your phone,
it's the stress throughout the day.
That one hour has probably eaten up two
hours of fucking cognitive time.
Now,
that two hours could have been spent
writing email marketing automations,
filming a YouTube video.
It could have been doing something,
creating content.
Now, two hours more a week
or four hours more a week,
let's say you do two calls,
that compounding effect
is a bigger following,
bigger fucking email list, you being
better at stuff. Those things can scale.
Getting good at sales calls can't.
So then you've got the time zones.
You should be running a global business.
If you're looking to go online,
you should be running a global business.
Global business means people aren't going
to be in your time zones.
Then you have the no-shows.
I fucking binned a podcast because one
cunt didn't show
up.
Johann Hari just didn't show up to the
podcast, like fuck this, dickhead,
podcast is shit, no longer doing it.
Some people will not show up,
and maybe their dog died.
But then you sit there thinking,
"This motherfucker didn't even respect me
enough to get on the call at the right
time." The no-shows kill you.
No one has a no-show then goes, "Oh,
let's go make some content.
I can't wait to make some content." They
do your fucking head in.
Also,
there's something called the menu effect.
Before I go to a restaurant,
before I go to a hotel,
I don't actually care how much it costs.
I just want to see what the rooms look
like.
And with the restaurant,
I want to see the menu.
You motherfuckers that are trying to say,
"I only discuss my pricing on calls,"
people are bouncing. People like me,
when I bought Ed Lawrence
course, I go,
"What's the most expensive thing you do?"
He goes, "This." Go, "Cool,
bye." There are so many people out there
like me, and if you withhold pricing,
bounce. Most people
are not going to fucking get there.
Would you go to a hotel
or restaurant without seeing the menu
or knowing how much
it's going to cost? Imagine I go, "Oh,
go here, it's an amazing place." "How much
is it?" "Oh,
you don't know till you get there." Fuck
off.
So,
so many of you think you're strategizing
for a way to make more sales, but the
stuff you are being fed
is fucking bullshit.
And
if you were to email me,
which I get, people send me long emails,
"Oh, James, I've been in memberships
before. Oh, I've been let down. Oh,
my last mentor this,
my last mentor that." I
don't even read the fucking email.
I just respond and go, "Hey, mate,
if you haven't made your fucking money
back in
three months, I'll refund you in full.
How's that?" Now,
that has taken me eight seconds.
So rather than jumping on a call for a
fucking hour, have eight seconds, and even
then I was being generous because most of
the time I don't talk to people that
don't give me money. And
that can sound like a really dickish
thing, right?
This call is one of the only times I will
ever talk
to anyone that has not given me money.
It's just the way I like to operate my
business.
It sounds bad,
but I've only got a finite amount of
energy, and I want to protect
it. Now, some industries do need a call.
Maybe you're an accountancy firm bringing
on a client, whatever it is.
But let's reframe
that into an onboarding call.
So instead,
let's say you're an accountancy firm,
you charge £7,000 a year.
I would say to someone like, "Look,
I can't give you a member of staff until
you
join, but how about this? If you join
and you pay us the £7,000, once that's
got to the accounts,
we're going to do an onboarding call.
However,
if in the onboarding call we don't have
exactly everything that we've
promised,
you have a 30-day no qualm money-back
guarantee." So I would even
make sure that the money's in the bank
before even putting anyone on a call with
someone,
because then you eradicate the time
wasted, the no-shows.
No one's going to go, "Oh,
I need to think about it."
If they're ready to pay
£7,000,
they're ready to do an onboarding call.
So the only sales call I'd ever have
is an onboarding one.
And some people go,
"But other coaches do them.
Other coaches do sales calls." Yeah,
because they're dumb. They're stupid.
They've been misled by their fucking old
mentor, and they're shit at fucking
content. They're shit at landing pages,
and they're shit at writing email
marketing
emails. And guess what? I
was for a few years, too.
But the skills that you can learn from
operating a funnel that doesn't need a
fucking sales call
is going to revolutionize not just your
business, but all the
other processes in it. Because ultimately,
if one of my videos goes
fucking mental overnight, which they do,
I've got YouTube videos that after four
months have gone viral, I just wake up
and the money's there.
I don't want to wake up to a busy fucking
calendar with loads of sales calls.
I don't want that. And some of you go,
"Yeah,
you could just get someone else to do
the sales calls." Or
just create a system where you don't
fucking need them
And those of you
that hide your pricing from your clients,
you're fucking snakes.
Right? And I get it. It wasn't your idea.
Other people told you
that you should be doing it.
Either way, you're fucking snakes.
You click on that offer,
you see the price that I'm offering you,
price first.
When I go to buy my car,
I don't give a fuck.
I like the fact it's expensive.
That's why I wanted the car. Now,
you wouldn't go to a Porsche dealership
and they
go, "Hey, sir,
you can go for a test drive,
then we'll show you the price." No.
When I went to buy my car, I said to him,
"I'm not touching this car or getting in
it till we can work out some fucking
numbers, bro." So yeah, it's not
scalable in my opinion. Now,
we spoke before about a landing page.
Landing page and a website
are two different things.
When we go to a website, About Me,
Contact Us, and then you've got
social icons, which
is pretty fucking stupid.
If I go to your profile, trust me, bro,
you don't want me clicking on your YouTube
because when I get to your YouTube
and your video's a bit boring,
I've clicked on
someone else's YouTube,
I'm now half an hour into a cook-along
with Andy Cooks,
and I'm never going back to your website.
A landing page is a page with one option.
If you go to the link in the description
to this video, you'll notice there is only
one place for you to go,
and that's to buy.
A squeeze page is where you get someone's
email address, only get an email.
Landing page,
only place you go to make a sale.
Now, for those of you that do a VSL,
this is your
opportunity. Okay? A VSL
is a video sales letter.
It is a video that you put on your landing
page.
Now,
you've all seen "8 Mile," you've all seen
the rap battle at the end.
"Fuck everybody. Fuck y'all
if you doubt me.
I'm a piece of white fucking trash.
I say it proudly." So
if you have done a load of sales calls,
that's great
because you now know all the objections.
So in your VSL, you get there
and you say to people, "Look, I get it.
You've been stung by business mentors
before.
People that told you you needed to DM 150
people a day and book people on
calls.
They told you you need to do high ticket,
and they got you to your first 10K
a month. Then they abandoned you
and never gave you the support
or the structures
that you need. Well, in my mentorship,
I actually teach you how to get good at
the
things that is very difficult to get good
at.
Social media, email marketing,
creating great landing pages,
and that's why you're
here,
where there isn't the ability to do a
sales call, but here's my guarantee.
If you don't absolutely love it
and make your money back in three..." You
see what
I'm saying?
All those objections you put into your
video sales letter.
Not, "Hi,
my name's James." They know who the fuck
you are, mate, because they've
just come from your email marketing
campaign they've been reading for 22 days.
You can just objection handle all of their
insecurities.
Then every three months of working with
people, you go back and you change your
VSL, you make it a little bit better.
That video should do all the sales for
you.
We then put pretty much all the
information from that in the landing page.
Now,
you might say,
what could someone get from a call they
couldn't get from a VSL?
I'm not sure.
I actually don't know because
if someone was
to watch one of my VSLs and go,
"I need more information," I'll go,
"You're
obviously a retard." And
that sounds harsh, but if you've watched a
three-minute video where I've explained
everything on a page that has all the
information and you still need a call,
then you're a retard.
I'm sorry,
and I don't want you to work with me.
Sometimes people will email me
and I'll go, "Hey, look,
here's the offer." Then
they'll come back and ask more questions.
I'll just leave them on air because no
offense, you're a retard,
and I'm not going
to bend over backwards to get a retard in
the ecosystem because you're ultimately
going to need more work than everyone else
because you're a retard.
And again, choice of language,
personal brand.
If someone sat there going,
" [gasps] Oh my God,
James just said the word
retard." You don't know the level of
learning difficulties that I've had.
I had to sit in the fucking cloakroom with
all the retards at school.
So I am a retard.
I got tested for dyslexia, dyspraxia,
ADHD, the lot. So my neurodivergence,
I am a retard,
so I can say what I want. Cool.
So if you're going to make a good video
sales letter in 2025, these
are some of the
things you need to do. Don't script it.
Okay? Don't script it.
People out there reading the teleprompter
like,
"Hi, my name's James.
Welcome to my business mentorship."
Listen, if you
can't sell what it
is you're selling in three minutes off the
cuff, you're a
retard.
So maybe don't even have a landing page.
Go back to recruitment.
Just sit there and tell me what the fuck
it is you do and how it's going to help
me. Three minutes maximum.
You're not fucking Oppenheimer doing a
Christopher
Nolan. All right? Three minutes maximum.
If you can't get across your value,
your guarantee, and your offer in three
minutes, you're a retard.
Don't introduce yourself.
Don't be a retard.
Solution and product first. Not,
"My name's James.
I used to play rugby for Berkshire Under
21s when I was
younger,
and I used to get petrol money playing for
Berk..." No one cares.
Tell me what it is.
It's a cohort course full of content
that's going to make you a fucking weapon
at
everything you do. And my goal is to...
Because I've got a little bit of a mental
issue, right?
You can tell I'm a little bit mental.
I want to be a black belt at everything.
At everything.
I've got track days coming up,
content creation, editing,
everything.
There's something wrong with me,
and that's what I want for my
clients.
I want them to obsess over every single
little detail because even
if I fall short, even
if I never become a black belt,
I will still be a highly
skilled brown belt, which
is higher than most other people.
So in that video, solution
and product first, what it is that you're
doing. I've created this.
I've created a community.
I will look at your stuff myself,
and I'll give you harsh feedback.
And do you know what?
Sometimes I am a little bit too cruel.
I'll be honest with you.
For those of you watching,
sometimes I'm very, very harsh,
but you need it.
I sometimes call my approach chemotherapy.
Now,
chemotherapy is not there to kill you.
It's there to inspire you to
survive and bounce back.
The worst thing I could ever do in my
mentorship is
go, "Yeah, looks good, mate." Also,
with the VSL, consider this.
Enjoy it.
Even this video, I'm actually enjoying it,
and I've done this before where I hit
record on the camera, start doing a video,
then I stop and I come back and go,
"James,
just fucking enjoy it." I even have to do
this some days where I'm driving
down the road just in no mood,
and I'm like, "James,
what a great day." I'm like,
"Yeah.
Do you know what?" So I hit record
and I go,
"My name's James Smith." Remember,
don't introduce yourself.
"Welcome to my business mentorship." I'm
just putting on a little bit of a smile.
This is where I help people get good at
making money online using social media.
And just that little bit of a smile
doesn't just mean
that the person watching it
can see that I'm enjoying it.
It makes me enjoy it more.
And there should be a flow to your offer.
There should be a flow in the things
that you talk about, and this
is how it should
look.
All right. Here we go.
We'll get into that in a second.
First of all, let's do some questions.
Luke's just popped up on my phone.
So when the boss comes up on the WhatsApp,
you know it's good.
Catherine Sargent, all right.
I'm definitely doing yours.
Catherine's a weapon.
I'll be honest with you.
It took Catherine nearly two years to pop
off.
I thought she was deserving of
that before,
but sometimes the algorithm can be
cruel, and I love seeing her success.
"I've been talking about the same thing
for over a year until a video I made was
good enough to do well.
I've probably done the exact same topic in
20 different
videos. Then one popped off, 71." So
Catherine Sargent, amazing at chin-ups.
Like you say there,
she did so many variations of the video.
The video stayed the same. She got better.
Cadence, pacing, setups, production,
B-roll, overlay.
These things may seem alien to you,
but when you click the link in the
description,
and do you know what?
I'll do it here as well.
If any of you are in my mentorship with
this, if you don't mind just commenting
and telling people what your experience
has been like.
Ryan Summers,
"Literally the last mentorship I was in,
DMDM, 50 a day,
working up to 100 a day. I hated it.
I'm so glad James has his method out
there.
Many gurus play on PT's lack of business
knowledge." Because it's hard to make you
a black belt in all of this business
stuff. And do you know what?
There should be no component of your
business that you hate.
Maybe creating the landing page for the
first time, you'll hate, but that's it.
Jay,
"How do you work out who's your ideal
client?
And do you need to determine this using AI
or research in the market?" Okay.
For any of you really new to working with
people, work with everyone.
Work with everyone,
because then it's only doing that,
that you can
understand who you like
and who you don't like.
When you look at your calendar and you go,
"God, you know what?
I actually don't like working with the
dudes as much as the girls." When you have
some people that are corporate dudes
and you're like, "Oh,
I don't have as much fun
with those.
I have way more fun with the builders."
It's only through testing many
different foods at Cheesecake Factory can
you determine what your regular is.
You've got to try something random at
Cheesecake Factory once in a while.
You've got to go for a pasta dish.
It's only through doing that that you can
realize that you're a BLT man for life,
with cheeseburger spring rolls.
So it's a bit like you've got to play the
field,
mate, to understand that.
Do you know what?
This is my biggest hack for you guys on
here.
Have you noticed I've not used AI yet,
or mentioned it, or whatever?
If you want to get ahead, get fucking
good at all of these things I'm talking
about to the point you never use AI.
Because right now it is so easy.
People aren't stupid.
People can see when something's done with
AI.
I'm now putting spelling mistakes
and using lowercase letters in emails so
that
people know it's not written with AI.
I actually think the next play before AI
takes over, and by the way,
I'm not saying AI is not going to take
over.
I'm saying we've probably got four
or five years till we're all fucked.
And if you listen to the Daniel Priestley
podcast, you'll know this.
The next five years,
as depressing as it sounds,
there's going to be the biggest
separation of wealth ever.
There are going to be people with
and people without.
And the reason that I'm trying to teach
you guys all of this stuff is I would like
more of you and myself to be on the side
of with.
I think it's going to be way darker
and way shitter and way more fucked than
anyone
can decide. I want to be mortgage-free,
debt-free. I want to have a big house.
I want a big fence.
I want security cameras and loads of dogs.
So that when AI does come in five years'
time and fucks us all, I'm
ready.
And you guys should be doing the same too.
But for the time being, I think AI
is cheapening your offer more than you
would
think.
Josh,
"What are your thoughts on trial reels?"
Imagine this, right? There
are people out there too scared to post
because they
don't want to lose followers. There are,
especially the big accounts.
They're shitting themselves they'll do a
post, it won't be well-received, so trial
reels was created for creators that
are too scared to post because Instagram
needs
a good cadence.
Instagram needs you to post more because
then more people stay on
the platform. Do I think it's a hack?
Not really.
You might get a few viral trial reels,
but again, most people using
trial reels just started posting more.
They started getting better at making
content because they were posting more.
They got excited over the shiny new thing
and did the thing that they should've
done in the first place. So they're okay.
I don't think it's the
new way. It's cool. It's a tool, but
I'm not as excited as everyone thinks.
Because now there's trial reels, right?
All your competitors have just upped their
posting frequency by 20 times.
There's now 4,000% more reels to compete
with.
So trial reels,
although I think it's giving you the
advantage, it's giving your
competitors the advantage as well,
which is one of the reasons why I kind of
want
people to
YouTube.
Adam,
"How can you put guarantees into your
coaching, especially if you do coaching
calls?
You can't force someone to do what's
required and then refund them.
You'll lose hours of work." Okay, Adam,
here's the way you do this, right?
You don't be shit.
If your refund rate is anywhere above 5%,
you're not doing your job well enough,
and you deserve to lose those hours,
right? If 20% of people
are asking for their money back,
you shouldn't
be selling what you're selling.
If 20% of meals get returned in my
restaurant,
I shouldn't be running a fucking
restaurant. You understand that?
Now,
you could be crying over the 5% refunded.
Let's look at Nutonic, for instance,
right?
We lose 100% of the money and the postage.
We lose everything when I refund people,
and I'm doing it out of my own pocket.
You might think I'm crazy,
but think about this for a second, Adam.
When I say to people, "Head to Nutonic,
21% off Black Friday discount.
Buy whatever you want,
I'll refund in full," I could get three
times the amount of
sales to refund a few people. So you,
with the guarantee,
you might lose six hours in one month,
but you might double your
fucking sales volume, bro.
You might also free up, by giving a
guarantee, you're not doing sales calls.
So you might be saving two to four hours a
week.
Then one person
in a blue moon will fucking ask for a
refund.
You've already earned those hours back by
not doing the calls.
So you have to be willing to free up a bit
of time on one side to get it back on
the other. Also,
it's good to have a guarantee because then
you can't be shit.
I've just sent off our Australian cans
back to the factory again to do another
version because I know
that my guarantee is so strong that if the
quality of our product isn't good enough,
I have to pay the price.
The same way you should have to pay the
price for that.
So you shouldn't be worried about refunds.
If you are, your product could be shit.
And also,
you just need to back the fact that
if you're good at what you do, not
many people will ask for a refund.
I probably refund someone once every three
and a half weeks for Nutonic,
and we've done four million cans.
We are doing nearly $100,000 a day
And that is the refund rate.
Because it's not the refund they want,
it's the
confidence and the aura in saying it.
And what if I told you this, Adam?
I don't offer the money-back guarantee for
you or the clients.
I do it for me. I need something
that makes me more comfortable selling.
I need something
that makes me a better salesperson,
and the money-back guarantee
helps me do that. It
is a selfish vendetta.
And again,
you know I said no one cares about you.
Maybe I don't care about you.
Maybe I give the money-back guarantee,
so I sleep
better at night. And
if someone asks me for a refund,
they deserve it because they're unhappy.
And again, bro, Adam,
if you don't refund someone,
you have someone out there who hates you,
and someone that hates you will
spread a negative message 10 times further
than someone that loves you.
If someone wants their money back,
you should go back to them and say,
"Of course.
Is there anything else I can do?
I'm so sorry this didn't live up to it.
Can I have some feedback,
please?" Because feedback from someone
that actually
invested money in you
is some of the most valuable feedback
ever.
So we can disagree on this.
You'll lose hours of work only if
you're shit. And the guarantee
is what a lot of people need to be
humble and to have the humility to be a
good salesperson, but also to be a good
coach.
Just because the money's in your bank
account doesn't mean it's all yours.
Don't forget that.
And by offering people the guarantee,
that will make you a
better coach.
Ken,
"What would I tell people to make me stand
out among other sports therapists
when we all work with the same people,
have the same goal of getting people
pain-free?" Ken,
I'm a personal trainer
amongst hundreds of thousands.
I've got the name James Smith.
I'm a white boy from Berkshire
in a highly saturated industry.
I've got no qualifications.
I've dropped out of uni.
I've got learning difficulties,
and we're all
saying the same thing, eat less,
move more.
How do I stand out?
Just keep turning up
and become very good at making content.
Get very good at communicating with
people.
If you dedicate the next three years to
getting good at all the things we're
talking about here, you'll stand out.
And here's another thing, Ken.
I was in these PT seminars back in the
day,
hundreds of personal trainers in the room,
hundreds of them.
The only person I ever recognized
was Jamie Alderton.
I never saw another face again.
There were so many points in my career
where everyone else just gave up.
So there are going to be a lot of people,
sports therapists like you, that do
in-person, and they want to get online.
Every time you hit a hurdle where things
get really fucking hard, just keep
going. Because every boundary you get to,
there are loads of your competitors
dropping off. That's my best advice.
Just keep going.
Musa, "Can I join the mentorship
if I haven't figured out the product
or service?"
You can, but I would advise against it.
I actually don't think you're a good fit.
If anything,
I actually would say unless you're doing
at least £1,000 online a month, it may
not be the best place to come to. So,
by all means you can,
but at the same time,
I'm just going to be honest with you,
most people have already got their toe in
online stuff.
They've already got socials,
probably between 1,000 followers
and above.
You can,
but it would make me uncomfortable
that you're not already making money.
Because what I want for people
is to make their money back in three
months, and if
you haven't even got your product figured
out, you might not make your money back
for a year or two years, and
that can make me uncomfortable.
Nemo, "Recording on iPhone
or content studio.
Some people think really having a good
studio might make it feel fake.
Do you feel fake right now with the
information?" iPhone
is fine to begin with.
Remember,
better the right message on the wrong
camera than the wrong message on
the right camera.
I've seen some really well-produced dog
shit in my life.
Okay, Obsession Car Detailing,
"I make these detailed videos about cars,
PPF, and
get barely any views.
Then I make some brain rot content
that makes no sense, gets
thousands. What's the point?
Does it get customers?" Okay,
your content is just not
setting it up right. So for instance,
you've just said here you do
PPF, et cetera.
No one on this call knows what PPF means,
bro.
No one else knows
that it stands for paint protection film.
No one knows.
No one knows the difference between a wrap
and PPF.
For people who are watching,
you can go to Denary Averson and get wrap,
and you
wrap your car,
but it doesn't actually protect the paint.
PPF is a lot thicker.
You also have self-healing PPF.
No one on this call knows what
self-healing PPF is.
If you get a brush
and you scratch the PPF on the side of my
Audi, then I leave it
in the sun, it fucking heals.
No one knows that you can protect your
paint with PPF. Your job
is to educate people.
The reason, and trust me,
people watching this are interested.
Also,
not many people on this call know
that it is a full business tax deductible
to wrap your car.
I can't write off my car,
but all those Neotonic wraps that get
eyeballs and people to take photos of it
is a tax deductible.
There is so much people
are genuinely interested about
when it comes to PPF and car
wraps.
You are just not making the content
interesting enough.
I guarantee,
just from the people currently watching
now, if you were to make
content about this, you could do it.
There's a video online,
peeling off PPF of the orange GT3 RS
that went off at the
Nürburgring.
People cannot believe the level of
protection it gives the paintwork
underneath. You have a content problem,
not a niche problem, because I
would fucking froth that bit of content.
All right.
And for any of you as well
that maybe haven't seen Content Mastery,
I actually can
give you a link for this now.
If you're not ready to join, there is
a link there for Content Mastery. Again,
it's one of those things. Coleman Works,
"Should I start posting on my new personal
Instagram with followers
or my new smaller account with no
followers?
It's an AI content business."
If the issue is the people
that follow you, like your aunt
and your cousins, so
sometimes you think you've got a head
start because you're using your personal
account that's got 700 followers,
I disagree.
Because remember how we spoke about the
algorithm
determining whether or not your content
is shit or not?
If your aunt and your uncle see it,
they might give it a double tap.
Your cousin might go, "Yeah,
see what he's doing," have a little double
tap.
But the problem is that by doing so,
they're not going to watch it.
The average view duration
is going to be poo,
so you might need to start from the
bottom.
That's why I started a new YouTube
channel, which we're on right now.
Now we're going to get into pricing.
This could be the daddy of this talk so
far.
First of all, when I see a Porsche GT3 RS,
I like the fact it's
expensive. People like expensive stuff.
You think your missus doesn't like the
fact that a Birkin handbag is really
expensive? Do you not think
that people are drawn towards expensive
stuff?
You should be proud of pricing.
Those of you that say high ticket
and you're
scared,
it's because you don't think you're worth
that much. And I'm not surprised.
You bought into a mentorship
that forced you to do it.
So we can disagree on these pricing rules
and we can get into it in the next
question part.
If people can't afford something,
that's fine.
Remember, pyramid attribution,
we only need the top 2% to buy.
Do you think Porsche and Ferrari
are crying about the fact people can't
afford
their cars? Have you noticed
that the most elite
Ferrari, Porsche, McLaren,
they don't run discounts for Black Friday.
Again, would you stay in a hotel
if it didn't show prices?
And also when there's a hotel that's
really expensive,
people want to stay in it.
Burj Al Arab in Dubai,
it's like a six-star hotel.
It looks run down as shit,
but because it's like fucking two,
three grand a night,
people want to stay there.
Again,
I used to charge a fifth of what I did for
the business mentorship a year
ago. How did pricing change? And this
is where we come into the continuum
of pricing versus demand. So there
are so many things
that do not have a fixed
price. Oil, Rolexes, plane seats,
Off-White trainers,
high demand cars.
A Porsche GT3 RS does not cost
that much from Porsche.
It costs more secondhand. Handbags,
Pokemon cards, domains, number plates,
all of these things,
the expensiveness of it
is based on how many people want it.
School holidays, for instance.
So many of you are happy to be bummed on
flights and
accommodation when you go away for school
holidays. Why is that?
Because more people want to go away on
school holidays than normal.
Those of you in the UK,
you get charged money to pick your kids at
term time,
but it works out cheaper than going away.
So imagine this as an exercise.
I get put in charge of starting a brand
new hotel in Sydney.
It's just been built and they go, "James,
we need help with marketing." I'd say,
"Cool,
we're going to give rooms away for half
price." And some people go, "Why the
hell are you going to give rooms away for
half price?" I go, "Well, no one wants to
stay there. That is a problem.
So we're going to give rooms away for half
price,
$100 a night." Right? So then they go,
"Okay, cool." Right?
So people are coming in the hotel.
Some people might go, "This is stupid.
You've got people in the hotel,
but they're not even paying enough to
cover their
expenses." Right. But
when you have people in the hotel,
you can get content of
people in the hotel.
People will then start to have good
experiences.
Then they'll leave and they go,
"We stayed at that hotel at the weekend.
It was amazing." Now
that feedback goes to other people,
then they tell their
cousin, "Oh,
I'm actually going there next week.
I'll stay in that hotel.
That's amazing." Then as the bookings
start to come in, the hotel can start to
increase prices.
Even for the first three to six months,
they can use that
opportunity just to get the content from
it.
My first business events,
even my first tours lost money.
But I needed to do the tours,
book out a venue for fucking 15 grand to
have 60
people come for the night.
Even though we lost four grand for the
evening, I got
to get pictures of the events to show
people what was happening so that when the
next tour came around, they were like,
"I want to come to it." So a hotel's
pricing is only based on how many people
want to stay in it.
In the onset,
you might have to lose money
or be cheap to get people in there.
The same with personal training.
I don't care if you've got a strength and
conditioning fucking qualification.
If you are empty, you need to be cheap.
You cannot be expensive
and empty at the same time.
So
for anything you do,
you have to be cheaper first.
My business mentorship started at $800 US.
Why? Because no one was in it.
Then as I got busier,
I could afford the luxury of having a
higher price point.
It goes with demand all the time.
Bit like crypto and the watch market fell
through the ass because when crypto
dipped, everyone sold their watches.
So demand is the real thing we need.
There are two rules you need to think
about. If you are full, you are too cheap.
How do I know? Because by definition,
you are fucking full.
My barber, he's like, "Mate,
can't fit you in." I'm,
"What do you mean you can't
fit me in?" He goes, "Mate,
I'm fully booked. You're too cheap.
I've got to put your prices up by $5." He
puts his price up by $5.
I think he lost two clients,
but he's doing
like 100 haircuts a week.
So he's making $500 more, minus two
clients, making $490 more. I said,
"Now every time you've got an empty chair
in
front of you, do a little add-in."
He's full again. Put your prices up.
I just keep telling my barber to increase
his prices because ultimately I actually
want my barber to be 80% full. Why?
Because even though I pay more for a
haircut,
there's now more availability for me to
get a slot at different times.
So if you are full,
you're too cheap because you're full.
You can't take on any more people.
Then you put your prices up
and eventually you
won't be full and you'll have spare time.
And if you're not full,
you're not marketing hard enough.
You should live in balance between those
two things.
You're either full or you need to market.
Never a difference in between that.
Okay,
we're going to quickly dip into the
questions for this.
Let's have a little look.
Kieran Shea share,
"My content has improved so much in the
last few months.
How and when do I market/pay for sponsored
ads?" Right.
Paid posts can work, but do you know what?
In fitness, I've never cracked them.
I've had over 125,000 people through my
academy, never run paid ads for it.
I think paid ads are also sold to you.
These business mentors are like,
"We're going to teach you paid ads." It's
a
competitive landscape.
Even for the business mentorship,
there's a lad called
Connor who is full time. His job is ads,
ads, ads.
You will not boost posts
and compete in this market.
And also I actually sometimes think it's
easier to get
views organically than it
is to do paid ads.
I know so many people
that have made it to millions of dollars a
year without ever
running paid ads.
Paid ads can seem like the distraction.
They can seem like, oh,
if you just get to a point,
you can do paid ads.
I would like to go through life thinking I
don't need to use paid ads,
and especially if you're in fitness, it
is very difficult.
Despite what anyone's telling you,
despite the dream that people
are telling you,
paid ads is fucked,
especially on small margins.
I think if you had 100K to put into paid
ads, I'd maybe just build yourself a
content studio, get an editor,
and go ham on creating as much content as
you can.
Because you can control the level of
content you put out.
You cannot control ads as well as people
think.
Daniel O'Sullivan,
"I'm a PT coach of 10 years.
I only have a Facebook account with 900
followers.
When I post a video,
it only gets five likes.
Any advice?" If you're making a piece of
content for one platform, why the fuck is
it not everywhere? Why
is it just on Facebook? Why
is it not on Instagram?
Why is it not on TikTok? Why
is it not on YouTube Shorts?
This is just indicative of lack of effort.
If you can't even be bothered to post the
same piece of content to different
places, you deserve fucking five likes.
I'm sorry, but you do.
Every single piece of content is a digital
asset ready for the internet,
and you pay that asset into different
places.
If I give you a bag of seeds
and you planted one seed in one part of
the garden,
you deserve to have a shitty shrub come
through.
I want you to be spreading the seeds in
all different parts because there's going
to be one part of fucking soil that's just
got elite fucking dead
dinosaurs in it,
and the nutrient's going to make a massive
tree somewhere in your
garden
And people go, "James, why
is my YouTube doing better than..." I
don't know.
"Oh, James, why is..." I don't know.
But I don't care.
If you're getting more views on one
platform than somewhere else,
great. But yeah, you're like,
"You've been doing this 10 years,
you've only got
900 followers." Bro, imagine
if I said to you,
"I've been training in the gym for 10
years.
I've never made any meaningful results."
You'd give me a fucking TED Talk.
"Oh, come on, mate,
you need to put the effort in." You'd be
like, "Look,
structure, discipline,
consistency." You're a PT,
you'd give me the Norse
level 10,000 chat. You'd be like,
"Come on, mate,
we're going to structure out a
plan.
You follow the..." You don't take your own
fucking advice.
That's what I'm saying, bro.
At the end of the day, I guarantee you,
you're
probably one of the biggest hypocrites
ever, right?
The people you work with,
you literally give them a formula for
success
to follow,
but you don't have one yourself.
The fact, 900 followers in 10 years,
it's not too late to change this round,
but I guarantee you've not been putting
your priorities in the right place.
And you becoming a better digital marketer
and business person, I
think,
will make your clients get better results,
too.
Nima, "Started my list in June,
200 people now.
Five months later,
I have my first two sales now.
They're on my list for five months.
Why does it take so long?"
People just need time. They need time.
They want to watch your journey.
They need to be able to trust you. Look,
some people on this Live are
going to buy my membership with the link
in the description with that heinously
cheap price.
They might have followed me for four
years.
But rather than getting caught up about
it, this is the game.
And there should be something sweet, Nima.
Imagine this, when you, later on,
give yourself a little pat on the back
because
you just fucking worked for five months to
win over a lead.
And in five months' time, one email
is going to get you 10 clients.
And in a year and a half,
when your friends think you're fucking
crazy, you're
going to send out an email one day
and make £10,000.
But it's only through eating shit.
That's the period you're in, I'm afraid,
Nima.
You're in the eating shit period.
And I ate shit for so many years.
Luckily, now I can barely remember it.
I can't even remember the taste of shit
because I've been at this for so long.
But I revel in the fact I wrote emails for
10 months before someone
bought.
Ten months of email marketing emails.
No one bought.
If you'd met me in my first two years of
what I did, you would've thought I was
fucking insane. I
was sat in Waitrose writing emails to
people that weren't buying,
putting out content to the fucking
internet, to people that were just
double-tapping it.
You keep eating shit for...
It's the layer cake.
The layer cake,
you've just got to keep climbing.
Musa, "Have a full-time job,
but I did get a client from a referral to
build them
a web app,
so I want to get more clients since
that one was a friend of a friend."
Sounds to me like you've got no marketing
in place.
And if you've got a full-time job, mate,
you need to really strategize this out.
How many web pages do you need to build
for how many people at what price point to
be better off? And also,
there's a sleep consultant
that I'm working with at the
moment,
and she's doing all this marketing to get
a one-hour call with someone, and
that's it.
She actually needs to get people on a bit
more of a retention business
where she talks to them a bit more.
If you're going to build a web app for
people,
you need to get your numbers right.
Is it five clients you need to work with a
week and two new clients a month?
You need to start mapping out what the
life looks like. You need to go all in.
Again, there are so many people that
look at all of this,
and they wonder why people
are doing better.
I do this shit full time.
You will never be better than me doing
this,
what we're doing right now,
with a fucking side job,
because I live and
breathe this shit all day, every day.
I don't even see my friends.
And if we were a professional team,
we're going to beat every
single semi-professional team.
Semi-pro teams never beat professional
teams because professional teams live,
breathe the sport.
Semi-pro have to be two different people,
and there's no
way you can get that energy across two
different domains.
[sniffs]
So, right,
we're just going to quickly talk about
user behavior, and this is going
to help your short-form content.
So I want you guys,
next time you're in bed,
to watch your partner
or watch yourself as you scroll on social
media.
I want you to have a little binge fest
later on Instagram Reels, whatever it is,
and as you're swiping away,
I want you to look at how much time do you
give people
before you scroll past. You guys,
I can tell on Hinge whether or not
I wanted to sleep with someone in half a
second, right?
So you guys don't even give that.
It's like boom, boom, boom, boom, boom.
The first three seconds of your content
is so much more important.
And I'll be honest, this is something
that I don't tell many people.
When I'm in the Discord
and I'm critiquing people's content,
if the first 15 seconds are shit,
I'll go report back.
And sometimes they go, "Yeah,
but what about the rest of the reel?" What
do you
mean, what about the rest of the reel?
You fucking murdered the hook.
No one's there, brother. They're like,
"Yeah, but how was the rest of it?" It
doesn't matter, they're gone.
If you butcher the first hour of a film,
don't worry
about the ending. No one made it there.
So the first part of content
is so much more important.
If you've got 10 hours to do a 10-minute
YouTube edit, allocate four
hours to the first minute.
Because if you do not respect the initial
part of the content, you will lose
everyone. The first three seconds
is 10 times more important than you think.
Again, no one likes you.
If you labor the point,
if you don't cut out the pauses,
if you breathe, if you make noises,
if you have chewing noises, [smacks lips]
people will leave. Nobody likes you.
Again,
even leaving a half-second pause before
you start would annoy me.
If someone got in a video
and went [inhales] today,
gone. You're gone. I don't like you.
Your lighting's not good enough,
you're gone.
If your audio's shit, you're gone.
If I hear the rustle of your jacket on the
mic, you're gone.
People do not like you.
You have three seconds to impress.
You've got to get in there.
You've got to give them all the
information they need.
It's why we need hooks. They
are already wanting to move on.
People's finger is already ready to
fucking flick away, and you need to stop
that. You need to become a master of that.
Statement hooks, question hooks,
counterintuitive hooks.
You need to also watch people
and other content that does really well.
Why did that piece of content do well?
Anything with over 100,000 likes,
think to yourself,
why did this video do well?
Another thing,
don't optimize for algorithms.
Optimize for humans.
Algorithms are pretty much all of the data
that we get from watching humans.
If you want something, for instance,
right, when you're next making a piece of
content, chop some fruit. In your hook,
cut into a bit of
pineapple as you're saying your hook.
Humans will be trying to decipher what's
happening. Not the algorithm, humans.
They'll go, "I'm listening,
but I'm also watching someone chop a
pineapple." And
then as you're doing that,
they're kind of waiting for how those two
worlds come
together. It'll improve your retention.
Also, if you can find something
that you can do that puts you in a flow
state, for
instance,
chopping fruit It also just calms you down
and gives you a certain
aura. Try things out.
It's very interesting content.
The way you bring yourself into shot,
the way you might move the phone,
the way you
do scene changes,
the way you pose questions.
So much of what you can do,
you can learn from other people, but
you have less than three seconds.
So,
another thing that I want you to do as
kind of homework from today
is I want you to
go to your favorite creators on YouTube
and go back to their very first videos.
Something you need to realize
is back in the day, my content
was so unbelievably
shit.
Someone messaged me the other day
and goes, "Hey, mate, I went back to your
videos from three, four years ago.
I couldn't believe how shit they were.
It was really inspiring." 100% do that.
Even Chris Williamson's first podcast,
both the guests didn't even have a mic.
There was a mic just in the middle of the
table, and they're just talking at it
from different sides.
Go look at Chris' earliest podcasts.
They're shit.
It's so good. Joe Rogan, back in the day,
using a webcam.
So many people,
if you go back to the onset
and the beginning of their journeys,
their content is honestly awful.
And by looking at that, I did a video
about Dr. Julie Smith.
Her content used to be terrible,
but she just turned up, did
the reps, and got better.
One of those things
that you really need to get into.
All right,
we're going to go into some questions for
here.
[inhales] All right.
Ah, AdamMC192,
"I actually really like your content,
mate.
You're a bit of a killer on YouTube." I've
just seen yours, so this didn't
even come from Luke.
"Do you recommend a pay-on-results
guarantee?
I refund you if you don't reach your fat
loss goal." Not really, because that
screams to me that loads of people don't
reach their fat loss goals.
I would instead say,
if you're unhappy with the level of
service or I don't
deliver on my promises,
the reason I say this is this, and Adam,
I'm sure you're
aware of this, right?
I've had so many clients over the year
that come to
me for fat loss,
but they just say they want fat loss.
That's not actually what they want.
Susan Green, my favorite ever client,
said she wanted to lose weight.
Four months in, I sat down with her
and I was like,
"You've not lost any weight."
And she goes, "James, to be honest,
coming in and training with you means
that I
don't drink in the evening before." She
goes, "I'm drinking so much less alcohol.
I feel so much better about it." Her being
honest with me, I said, "All right,
Susan,
instead of doing three sessions a week,
why don't you come and see me for
half an hour every morning?" So we did
9:00 a.m. till 9:30 every morning.
She'd do her own warm-up, whatever.
That meant Monday to Friday,
I now stopped my client from drinking
alcohol
because she knew she'd see me the next
day,
and she knew I could smell it on her if
she had. Or she'd come in, and she'd go,
"Oh, I had a bottle of wine last night,"
whatever.
So many people come to you for fat loss,
and they get so much more
from it.
They get so much more than they expected.
So I wouldn't say if you don't get your
fat loss results because some people are
going to start training with you,
and actually, after two, three months,
they might
go, "I don't even care about fat loss.
I just want to feel good."
And through training
and feeling like I'm progressing
and getting stronger,
I'm actually getting...
What they wanted was to be happy.
And happiness and fat loss rarely
correlate as strong as other people think.
So,
what I would say to that is
the guarantee, put it on their happiness,
because that's what they want.
Okay. Quickly,
we're going to look into reframing,
and this is one of the easiest
hacks that you can put into your content
to do better.
So remember we said no one cares about
you.
They might still care about your story.
So if you're going to do a video on I lost
four kilograms in four weeks, make it
how you can lose four kilograms in four
weeks.
So if I've just lost 4kg in four weeks,
I don't go, "Hey, guys, I've lost four
kilograms in four weeks.
Come along for the journey." You go,
"Imagine if it was
possible that you could lose four
kilograms in four weeks without having to
even
give up food. To prove how easy this is,
I just went on a little experiment.
I'm going to share with you how you can do
it, too." Framing.
Rather than me going how I grew my
business mentorship to a $2-million-a-year
business, I go,
"I'm going to teach you how you can grow
your business up to $2
million.
I know this because I've proven it
firsthand through operating my business
in the last year." Now, again,
you might do a video,
20 things I wish I did
differently starting a business.
That could be 20 things you should
consider doing differently before starting
a
business.
Rather than me doing a video on how I grew
my social media to five
million followers,
here's a strategy for how you can grow
your followers to naught
to five million followers.
Everything here, guys,
is about solving people's problems.
You want to know the biggest hack to
making money? Solve problems.
Biggest hack to personal brand?
Solve problems.
Everything here is about solving people's
problems, and there's going to be a
law of reciprocity to this.
So let's imagine you've got a neighbor
called Bob,
and you put his bins out every single
week.
One week,
when you forget to put your bins out,
you know Bob's going to put your
bins out for you. Same way,
if you keep turning up,
keep solving people's problems,
even this right now
is about solving your problems.
If you do this for long enough,
people will feel obliged to buy your Black
Friday
discount offer,
the link in the description. Cool.
We're going to look into a few more
components. Very, very important stuff.
I'll get through as quick as I can.
There is a certain amount of emails
that you
need to have a million-dollar database.
I know this sounds cringey, right?
For some of your businesses, it's 5,000.
For some of your businesses, it's 100,000.
But there is a finite amount of emails
that you need to create a
million dollars.
And it doesn't matter where
that number is.
You need to start moving. If it's zero,
that's the only thing I will not accept.
There is a certain amount of emails you
need to get a million-dollar business.
20% of your audience should be your email
list.
If you don't have 20% of your audience
from your email list, your focus is in the
wrong place.
That should be your golden rule.
Where most people have stagnation in their
business, they have stagnation of their
email list.
If you double your email list size,
you will often double your
business. This livestream, right,
I managed to fix it, but I was doing
one of these not too long ago,
and the connection just dropped out.
The connection fucked up,
lost connection to everyone,
and all I did was follow
up with an email,
"Sorry the livestream cut out for whatever
reason.
Here's my offer." Ten grand, one email.
Even a fucked up livestream
was completely fine because I had
everyone's email
addresses, and you best believe that
if you don't click the link in the
description, get the offer,
I'm going to email you guys afterwards
anyway with the
offer to make sure
that you fucking buy it.
So having the data first
is such an important,
integral part to running a business.
Now, I'm going to say this again.
I've got some accolades behind.
$20 million drinks brand,
three number one bestselling books,
whatever.
I'm either the luckiest person in the
world, or
this shit works. And again, if you'd said,
"James, what's the single biggest
component that's allowed you to do well?"
Emails.
So we need to create something called a
squeeze page.
Now, lead magnet, squeeze page.
I call it a squeeze page because I squeeze
people
of their email address. Now,
I have some that you see in the links on
my YouTube,
30 days, 30 ways.
I put people where I just give them 30
days of information.
I'll explain why. There
was a guy back in the day who-- And again,
I copied this,
standing on the shoulders of giants.
There's a guy from Northern Ireland
And he said,
"50 ways in 50 days to improve
your business." So I sign up,
this guy emails me every single day for 50
days
telling me how to better my business.
On the 52nd day,
he tells me to buy his book.
I didn't buy his book.
He then adds me to a broadcast.
Now, an automation is an automation.
Broadcast is on top.
And he broadcasts every day,
and they're pretty good emails.
But one day he sends me an email drunk
from his dad's funeral,
and you can tell he's drunk from the
email.
Then at the end it says, "PS,
if you think it's inappropriate for me to
sell to you
off my dad's death,
go fuck yourself." It
was the best email I've ever read to this
day,
and I bought his book off the back of
that. So I was inspired from that.
I have a lead magnet for my fitness
business.
Also,
there's another lead magnet squeeze page I
have where if you ever see me do
these videos where I critique people's
social media, when people apply, I chuck
them into the 30-day automation. Now,
the beauty of that is, for some reason,
people that apply for a roast,
when we add them to the 30-day funnel,
we get double the attribution of sales.
Why? No idea.
And I think it's quite good as a business
owner to tell you that.
There would've been a squeeze page where
you guys signed up for this event.
That was actually a squeeze page.
So we had organic
and a little bit of paid, but I
can do paid because my margins are lovely.
So because of that,
yeah, the funnel was social media,
organic, paid, squeeze page,
get your email,
send you the link for this live stream,
then present to you, give you the offer
afterwards. Now, autoresponders,
I've said this a few times,
autoresponders are
email automations we can set up.
Some of you,
when it comes to having a lead
magnet, might not have a good one.
So for instance,
this is one of my highest converting lead
magnets where I realized there was a
problem. The problem was people
were making shitty landing pages.
So I was like, "Hmm,
I'm not going to be like build a better
business lead magnet."
I instead was like, "Cool, here
is a template of how to build a highly
converting
landing page." So I created this,
I printed out the asset,
and I send people this,
and I give them some more nuance,
but then I have 11
emails that follow up with them,
and it's those automated emails afterwards
that
actually bag the sales.
So even some of you, if you don't have a
physical product or offering to give to
people, you
can just create an automation
that has the value.
When people get an asset, automation.
When people join your trial, automation.
Automated emails can be as long as you
want.
You can set up as many autoresponders as
possible.
I once thought about writing email
marketing emails for a year
and then retiring, so
when anyone joined my email list,
all the emails were
pre-done.
But I still think people need a little bit
more than
that. With those automations,
maybe give them a bit of breathing room
for the first
two days, then sell every day. In sales,
buy or die.
At the end of the day,
you can't be too pushy in an email as long
as it contains
value, entertainment or humor,
or whatever.
So autoresponders,
fantastic way because some people go,
"I send one
email a week." I'm like, "Motherfucker,
one email a week is lazy as shit."
When you buy it or you consider getting an
Eight Sleep, they email you every single
day, and that's what I want.
Imagine you join my lead
magnet and I email you once a week. Cool.
But imagine you join my lead magnet
and then I email you every day for the
next
30 days. In 22 days' time,
you have one day you lose three clients, I
hit you by email. The same way,
I want you in people's email fucking
inboxes when a button pops on their jeans
when they sit down at work.
I want you to be in there
when a dude gets dumped by his missus who
was too hot for
him.
You need to be there every single day to
turn up for these people.
It is unacceptable to email less than
daily, in my opinion.
Five emails a week minimum,
maybe have weekends off.
Now,
you motherfuckers also need to get
domains.
My mate Paul Alima launched a B2B course
at the weekend, and he fucking had a
support email from a Gmail.
I messaged him straight away and I went,
"Mate, nah,
you cannot be operating a business from a
Gmail, a Yahoo, or an Outlook account."
Why? Imagine I'm getting married
and I get recommended a
fucking wedding videographer, and it was
johncamerawedding@gmail.com.
Not getting the business. He's just not.
Because it screams to me you're part-time.
If you couldn't buy a domain for fucking
$12, I don't trust you.
You should not be sending emails from
Gmail. I get cold emails all the time.
If they come from a Gmail,
block straight away.
How big and long should it be?
That's what she said.
For an email,
I reckon no more than three minutes.
If you can't read it in three minutes,
it's a fucking novel.
Belongs on
Substack. That's what it's called. Okay.
There's a guy called Jerry Seinfeld,
comedian, writer back in the
day. Not sure if you guys know this,
but I thought I'd remind you.
He made a promise to himself
that every day he'd spend two days in a
room on his
own, no phone, no laptop, nothing,
just for ideation, and he
never ever said that he had to come up
with content.
He just had to do the two hours. So
if Jerry Seinfeld
was going to sit in a room
for two hours, distraction-free,
to come up with material, you guys can
spend five, 10 minutes, even if it's
when you next go for a drive.
No music,
no podcast, no YouTube.
Shouldn't be YouTube-ing
when driving anyway.
But next time you go for a drive,
just spend that half an hour thinking.
Thinking of ideas.
If Jerry Seinfeld could sit in a room for
two fucking
hours,
you can start allocating some time to get
creative.
If you don't have a good lead magnet,
go sit in a field until you do.
All right.
Let's get some questions before we get
into the landing page
debacle.
Okay. Lewis Voss,
"I work in a private gym.
Working the floor isn't really an option.
What's the best way I can go about getting
more clients?"
Working the floor. Okay, cool.
Online would be your only way to do it
really,
which is going to take a long time.
You've opted to work in a place where
there's just not thousands of prospects.
Fitness First has many things wrong with
it, but you have an abundance of prospects
there. If I was to say, "Lewis, what
is your social size and email size?" That
would probably give us the problem there.
So yeah,
you are months away from getting your
first online client if you do it
right.
Aaron Gawke, "Regarding full-time,
part-time,
I have a corporate job in another
industry,
but want to diversify to help dads with
their fitness journey.
Would your course assist with the
diversifying?" Yeah, but why help dads?
Why?
I think that's too niche, bro.
It's too niche.
Dads are what?
A third of the adult population
Bro, if you're a dad, you have a partner,
even if you're divorced, and you
have a child.
You have two things in life that
are fucking incredible.
Do you know what cohort of men need you?
People that are single and people that
are childless.
To me,
everything boils down to pain points,
right?
The people that buy my Black Friday offer
are the ones right now who are
struggling. It's people
that need fucking help,
not people cruising on
100K a month. You want to work with dads.
I don't care if I get fat,
if I've got a beautiful partner who's
understanding, and
I've got my son that I can hold at night.
If you want to go after men,
go after the 28 or 32-year-old
men who are single, fat, fucking losers,
worried they're
never going to meet someone of their
dreams, and go turn
that person's life around.
Why you would go after dads
is just moronic to me.
Go after men that need to fucking
revolutionize their life.
There are men out there
that need to stop drinking,
that need to start working on
themselves,
and they need to increase the level of
status they are so they can find
a fucking mate. So although you go, "Oh,
I'm a dad, we'll
help other dads," if you spent a bit of
time with actual real people,
helping a dad get jacked, cool, sweet.
Helping a man improve his life,
to find love, to end up having
children.
Men are much luckier in that regard.
They can turn their life around at 40
and still be fine.
So maybe that's something
that I would say for that.
If you're in a corporate job, it's safe,
but eventually, you're going to have to
make the leap, and every month
and year you leave it, you
are going to run out of
time and energy. You think
being a dad, the older you're a dad,
the less energy you have with your kids.
But you got to decide what you want to do.
Every year you're in the corporate world,
and again, nothing wrong about having a
corporate job.
I miss not giving a fuck about stuff.
But every corporate job
is going to suck the maximum amount of
energy and life out
of you for the least amount of money,
and you cannot change my life on that.
They will. Elbad, "I'm an in-person PT.
It's a good idea to create a free email
autoresponder lead magnet to give to
members of the gym, send them free advice,
then use that to gain clients." Sure,
but do not give free advice.
No one woke up today wanting free advice.
For instance, this isn't, "Hey,
do you want some free advice
for your landing page? Hi,
do you want some tips?" No one woke up
wanting tips.
Hey,
do you want more fucking conversions from
your sales page?
Do you want to stop leaving money on the
table?
Because people do wake up going, "Oh,
I wish I didn't leave so much money on the
fucking table." Because the pain point
here is that when people use this,
if their conversions go from 1% to 2%,
they've doubled the amount of revenue for
no
extra energy. That's why that
is a good lead magnet.
So anyone want any tips?
If you put your lead magnet on a sign
and went to the high street,
would people stop you?
If no, think more, do better.
So yeah,
you could put together a squat university
workshop, maybe not Squat
University as a brand.
You could call it the Squatmania,
something where it's like a fucking
perfect your squat.
Then every single person who's seen the
squat rack, you're like, "Hi, my name's
Elbado3.
Not to say there's anything wrong with
your squat.
Here's a little QR code on a business
card.
If you scan this,
you're going to learn how to get a perfect
squat.
Do this. Honestly,
the majority of people I've given it to
have put 20 kilograms on
their squat in three months,
and it'll make sure you don't injure
yourself.
Feel free to use it, whatever."
Nima, cool. "Busy today.
Thoughts on running two YouTube channels
at once because
you have two things you want to talk
about." Now, if you've got two businesses,
cool.
If you have two things you want to talk
about, don't just have a YouTube
channel because you want to talk about
stuff.
Let me remind you,
the only time I'm on social media is
when I want sales.
I do not like talking about things.
I do not like having to offload my son to
his grandparents this morning to
come do this. I like sales. I like money.
I like that some of you
are going to end up joining my mentorship.
I do not talk on social media for it.
You know, Paul Mozie and that,
all these people
that have sold for hundreds of
millions,
if we sell Nutonic for $100 million, you
will never see me on social media again.
If we sell for a billion,
I will delete everything. I'll be gone.
Poof.
So
don't create a YouTube just because you
want to talk to people.
Create YouTube if there's a business need.
And if there isn't a business need,
save your energy. Train with Dev.
That's got to go with that handle, mate.
Train with Dev.
Because I guarantee, right, no one
is going, "Oh, you should check out
Train with Dev." They'll go,
"Dev's my trainer. Fucking legend.
Fucking legend.
Meet Dev. Dev, meet John. John, Dev. Dev,
John.
Train with Dev." Nah. Because you
are currently just
for training now.
There's no brand morphization there.
Aaron Peas,
"What's a good starting point for an
online coach in terms of price?
When I'm not full,
I currently ask for 300 a month,
believe I'm worth it,
struggling to get clients.
Should I lower this?" You're probably too
expensive.
Now,
I would say to take your hourly rate
and charge a week for the
hour. So let's say you charge £45 a
month. First of all,
I would offer people weekly, because
when people think about
PT, they often think about weekly, right?
They don't think about monthly,
because 300 pound a month,
if you want to do
monthly pricing, people
are going to compare it to their mortgage.
They're going to go,
"300 pound a month for PT?
Mate, my mortgage is only 800. What?
You want me to pay half my mortgage for
PT?
Fuck off." But if you said it's £45 a week
and you offered weekly pricing,
some woman comes home and goes, "John,
I'm thinking of getting a PT again."
"Oh, yeah?
How much?" "45 pound a week." "Oh, yeah?
And it's all online.
Oh,
that's good." So the pricing side of
things, what's that?
45, 45, 99, 180, let's say. Then
when you want to increase prices,
when you're full,
you go from 45 a week to 50 a week.
Then also by putting up your prices by
just £5 versus 20, it seems a lot
more sensible when in line with inflation
or whatever you want to call it.
So if you're currently asking for 300 a
month, I guarantee you're just doing it
because that's what everyone else does.
But if you're struggling to get clients,
you're too expensive, and you should have
a weekly offer,
and it should be in line with your hourly
rate.
Now,
the first week you have with a client,
you'll probably have to spend an hour
or more onboarding them
and doing everything.
But as time goes on
and you retain clients,
the amount of time you spend with them
is less and less.
Some clients we service in six minutes,
you still get £45.
Lewis Voss,
"Would you offer free sessions
and then convert to paid in the onset of
a PT business?" I would give people a free
session, and then I would sit down with
them and pitch. Hope you enjoyed that.
That was just a showcase of my training
style.
This is how I'd get you to go through your
goals. This is how much it costs.
If at any point in your first month of
training with me, you don't love it,
it's...
I also have a PT starter kit, by the way.
Zafir Sheikh,
"How to offer a money-back guarantee on a
medical consultation
considering I won't solve 100% of
patients' problems?
If you're not happy with the consultation,
I'll give you a full refund." Yeah.
And mate, if I said to you
that only 1% of people ask for a refund
and it got you
twice as many bookings, would you do it?
If so, do it.
Rhea Coles,
"I've been working with a marketing agency
for about six weeks who are
handling my social media.
My views have grown massively.
Just wondering,
should my content differ across different
platforms?" All right.
This marketing agency could be great,
right?
Probably not across different platforms
such as long-form or short-form.
But by offloading shit to a marketing
agency,
I guarantee they're bumming you dry
as well.
I bet you're paying a lot of money for
that. Do you not understand?
You need to be getting good at this stuff.
You could just get a marketing agency,
but I need you to become the expert.
I hired some people recently,
I won't go into the details, but they
were doing a
subpar job,
and I could only spot it because I'm a
fucking weapon on
YouTube. Now,
if you have a marketing agency, they
are going to slack in a
department of your business, and
if you do not learn these things,
you will never
know that.
If you offload your thinking to someone
else, you will get the thinking
of someone else. Now, good friend of mine
hired someone on £40,000 a year, which
is fine,
and he offloaded a lot of his critical
thinking to this person.
And do you know what happened?
His ideas became 40K a year ideas.
If you leave your ideation,
your creativity, and your marketing to
someone on a salary,
you will never get ideas better than
that salary.
So [coughs] you get an agency,
you pay them £10,000,
you're only going to get
£10,000 worth of business.
When you pay me,
you're paying me to make you better,
right?
You're paying me to level up your own
understanding of all of these things
because do you know why my businesses do
well?
Because I am a good marketer
and I've learned to become a good
marketer.
And I learn good marketing.
And the better I get at marketing,
the better I spot it
everywhere else.
I am a fucking nightmare in Nutonic
headquarters
because I am such a good fucking marketer
that when we hire people to do our
marketing,
I can spot the fucking holes in it
straight away.
Now, the big issue is,
if you do not learn all of these things,
you will hire
people and they will take you for a
fucking ride.
Muavi Arif,
"Where should you start as a beginner?
No email marketing, no landing page,
just Instapage." Start with a squeeze
page.
If you get one email address in the next
week, it's progress.
Dan Devonside,
"How many hours of one-to-one experience
should you get before you
start online coaching?
So many fuckers jumping the gun going
straight online with
zero experience." They will never survive,
they'll never do that well, which is
good.
I would say at least 1,000 to 2,000 hours.
And then even if you get in there early,
just keep doing in person until you're
ready to make the jump.
It's very rare that you would go full-time
online
without that experience because people can
spot it.
And that's what you're paying me for.
All these questions you're asking me I
know because I've answered them 1,000
fucking times. Saro Dog Training,
"For dog training niche,
do I bother with sales
calls for my high-ticket program?" So my
dog trainer sent me a well-written PDF
with the pricing. It
was $800 for the first few lessons.
I was like, when I saw his prices,
I thought, "Fuck me, he must be good.
Booked." I don't think you need a sales
call.
I will help your dog do X, Y, Z
or your money back,
or I'll keep working with them
till they do. Now,
dog trainers,
so many of you online
are trying to put out content
that impresses other dog
trainers. Stop.
Start talking to your prospect. Hooks.
Do you want your dog to walk off the lead?
How do you get your dog to come back
when you call its name?
Even the term recall, don't use it.
Just speak to them like normal fucking
human beings.
If you want your dog to come back
when you call its name,
try these three things.
Why not to give your dog a treat on a
walk?
Why your dog behaves in the house,
but not overseas?
How can you prevent your dog from getting
in incident with other dogs?
Should you... All of these things.
There are so many important aspects to dog
training that people miss out on.
And do you know what? Here's one for you.
This is a funny one.
One weekend I had my son
for 48 hours on my own,
and a dog trainer joins the
mentorship, and he had a kelpie.
I've got a kelpie.
And he asked a couple questions on a
Friday night,
and I couldn't get back to him
because I had my son.
And I got back the next day,
and I could see he was a bit
arsey about it. I just refunded him.
I refunded the guy, whatever.
And the next day I emailed him and I go,
"Bro,
if you'd just been a bit more chill,
I could've helped you so much." Because
I have been through the hurdles of hiring
a dog trainer.
I've had shit dog trainers
and I've had good dog trainers.
I know so much about what people with a
dog want.
And being a dog trainer, you
forget what it's like to call your dog
and it doesn't come back.
So you need to really,
really get yourself down to the level of
your clients and
the people you work with.
Some people just want their dog to look at
them when they
say their name.
They don't want their dog to jump over
hurdles and go through
fences and do all of this fucking shit.
They just want the basic stuff.
And if you can say,
"I will get your dog to come back to you 9
times out of 10 when
you call its name,
or I'll give you your money back." This
is the thing, right?
My dog never even achieved half the stuff
I wanted him to, but the
halfway point, I'm happy.
My dog doesn't do half the shit
that I wanted him to, but he now sits
before crossing the road so he doesn't get
hit by a bus.
Out of all the money I've spent on dog
training, thousands of dollars, the fact
that my dog now sits before the fucking
busy road,
worth every penny.
So even the guarantee
that I got from my dog trainer, it doesn't
matter.
We got half of the way I wanted to
and I'm happy.
So as long as you can help people,
be happy. That's it.
He's a fucking bastard though because he
then runs down to the beach.
Sophie Waddington,
"Can a free community be a lead?" No.
So
free communities, who's managing that?
You. This is how it should be, right?
No one should get anything for free.
Maybe a live stream like this where you've
got a link in the description.
But you might go, "But James,
you've got one of the biggest TRT groups
for men in
the world." Yes,
after they bought a blood test.
The only way they're getting any
interaction is after they bought
something.
If you want a free community,
why have all these people chatting within
each other?
How about this?
How about you grow a fucking email list
and your community is 1,000
people on an email list,
and how about you send those people a
fucking offer every
day with a really cleverly written email?
Musa,
"Is the mentorship only available for
coaches?" No, I've got accountancy
firms, got marketing firms,
got people in B2B.
I've got lads that run an ayahuasca
business.
I've got big YouTubers. I have everything.
Because this is the thing people don't
want to understand, right, Musa?
Every single business has the same
problems, every single one,
across all of it. Across all of them.
It actually doesn't matter what you sell.
Marketing, for instance.
When I make you better at marketing,
it's going to
improve your ability to get laid. Now,
getting sales for a
business online and fucking someone can
seem so disconnected, but
it's exactly the same.
You talk to a certain amount of people,
you get a certain amount of numbers.
A certain amount of numbers,
you convert into a certain amount of
dates.
A certain amount of dates,
a certain amount of people
are going to put out.
That's it. Now, you might go, "Sales
and fucking is different." It's not.
Because really what you're looking for
is the win over a client, and really what
you're looking for is to get laid. Now,
not in all cases.
Sometimes you get a single transaction,
but sometimes that
transaction is so good you want
that transaction again,
and you go into the
renewals process.
Now the renewals process
is a relationship.
So renewals in business, relationship.
Now, that renewals process will keep going
until one side of the party lets down its
agreement.
Then you'll go back to tender
and look for new partners.
So marketing, fucking,
all of these things are the same.
All of them are the same.
Now you might go,
"It doesn't apply to my business." I
fucking doubt it.
Because it's all the same marketing.
Social media, get people attention,
bring them away,
put them into email marketing,
maybe even SMS.
Send them an offer on a daily basis until
they feel compelled to
agree to that offer. Give them a menu.
Let them read the menu. Let them buy.
When they buy, retain them.
Unhappy customers, get a refund.
Happy customers, grow your business.
Ria calls, "Just to clarify,
regarding the marketing agency,
I don't pay a lot.
They're based in India.
Enables me to have way more time to focus
on my actual daily business instead of
creating posts daily."
Okay. I like that.
Time to focus on my actual business
instead of creating posts daily.
There is part of me that goes,
maybe someone else could run the business,
and you
could create more posts daily,
but most marketing agents...
So we've hired several for our coaching
app, and they've all just been fucking
wastes of time.
And they audit your business to give you
the, "Have you tried this?" "Yes."
Kamala B.,
"Currently going through a PT course.
Thinking of starting making content based
on my body transformation and what I
learned so far.
Should I be joining?" You could,
but remember what I've said.
No one cares about your body
and your transformation unless the
lesson's for them.
So as a PT, I can't stress this enough.
No one gives a fuck about your lunch.
No one gives a fuck about your workout.
No one gives a fuck about your
transformation.
Any PT can get in shape for clients.
What they care about is their problems.
So when you get into the industry,
stop taking pictures of your lunch.
Instead, focus on other people's problems.
Okay,
we're going to quickly go through a
landing page. I did tease you before.
You're not here, not there,
you're teasing me.
So landing page.
Rather than you having to download this
asset, let's get into it.
A landing page is where you go to to try
and get someone to buy stuff.
Squeeze page, email, landing page
[clicks] is where we want to get a sale.
We have the VSL at the top.
Now on top of the VSL, that video,
we want to have a heading.
[paper rustling] The heading should be a
promise, an outcome that you can
understand.
Give up smoking without cravings.
Whatever it is.
Make more money online without DM'ing
strangers.
The subheading could be like,
"Create a strategy that automates sales
whilst you go to bed." "Learn how to give
up smoking without suffering with all the
cravings that come through." There's your
VSL right there.
Now this bit here should all be above the
fold. Above the fold.
So many people put branding up here
massively.
You can have a tiny bit of branding,
but not too much.
If you have too much branding here,
then half your VSL isn't there above the
fold.
I do not want anything like
that [paper rustling] because so many
people are going
to bounce before they even scroll down.
They're having a little look at your
landing page.
So we want it to be the flow is this way,
right?
What it is,
is the first thing we want to talk about.
What is it?
Is it a coaching program?
Is it a mentorship? Is it a system?
Is it an e-book? Is it whatever it is.
What it is, what they get.
What do they get from what it is?
Then why they need it.
What it is, what they get,
why they need it.
So let's do it for this business
mentorship. What is it?
I've created a community of businesses
that want to grow through sharing
information with each other
and having me critique their content,
their landing
pages,
and to have valuable coaches in the
ecosystem. What they get.
You get loads of different courses from
what to put on your Instagram bio, how to
create better short-form content,
how to create a YouTube channel,
how to run a
business, all of these things.
That's what they get.
You also get a Discord where you can
communicate with me and other members,
pose
questions. Even little things,
like some people will come into the
Discord, "Hey,
anyone else using Everfit?
Is it good?" Then someone else goes, "Oh,
I used
it. Now I use this." "Oh, great.
How much does it cost?" Those things
talking to
each other is a massive benefit.
Why they need it.
Well, most of you
are trying to do this on your own.
It's very lonely running a business.
I know this because none of my friends
are making as much money as me, so I'm at
the racetrack on my own.
None of my friends can afford Porsches.
Very, very lonely.
So sometimes you need people at the same
level as you so that you can bump ideas.
"Hey, guys.
Thinking of doing this for a lead magnet."
Someone else goes, "I
actually tried that.
It bombed until I did this." So this
is another thing.
Not only is it the information
that I give people,
it's all the information they
get from other people. Why they need it.
Because you're lonely,
you need to float ideas. Imagine this.
Yesterday, someone says, "Hi, James.
I've got three lead magnets.
Not sure which one to go with." I go,
"Does one perform better than the others?"
"Yeah,
this one dominates by far." "Just focus on
that one." "Thanks, mate."
Another person,
"Why did this video not do well?" "Hey,
mate, you paid off too
early. Next time, do this, this, this,
then pay it off." "Great." Another video.
"Can anyone help me with this title
and thumbnail?" Give them three variations
on
it.
Do you know some people only get 10
minutes of my time a
month, and it can just give them
that little bit of feedback they need.
Sometimes you just need people with a
little bit more experience.
How much it costs.
I think it's like 2,000 US dollars,
which hopefully next year...
I'll be honest with you.
I'm working towards making my mentorship a
$6,000
product, and I've already gone,
"I've to hire some more staff
and get some more
demand."
But considering I've got 50,000 YouTube
subs in two years,
I'm doing about two million US dollars a
year with it at the moment.
I think 2K is pretty fucking good value.
And why to believe me.
Why to believe me is this fucking live
stream.
So the flow of my VSL. What it is,
James' Business Mentorship.
What they get, the Discord,
all of the courses, and future access.
It's a lifetime membership.
Not like those fucking
mentorships that Do you dirty
and keep charging you on a monthly
rate. Why they need it? Access to me,
access to community. How much it costs?
$2,000 US. Why to believe you?
Because I just spoke to you for fucking
two and a
quarter hours without taking a piss break
just to get you fucking across how
good this is. How to pay?
There's a link on there.
Now, there are different pages
and platforms you can use.
I do love one that's called Leadpages.
The reason I like Leadpages is
that you get the analytics from it,
and also some of
you may not realize
[paper rustles] when you have a landing
page like this,
you will get a certain conversion rate,
let's say 3%.
Then you go dark mode, you make it dark,
you make the text light.
Suddenly you're at 3.2%. You go, oh,
dark mode works better.
Then you change your heading.
And on landing pages, you can create four,
five variations of the exact same page
and just make little tweaks to it,
and then
you can look at the analytics.
And the good thing
is you just share one link with
everyone, and that one link
that you share with everyone,
they then split the
traffic across it.
So it helps you become analytical.
On YouTube at the moment,
we test three thumbnails, three titles.
Why?
Because we need to know
which one works better.
So sometimes we need to A/B split test
stuff, and this isn't something for a
marketing agency, this
is something for you.
Your title might be fat loss,
your title might be muscle growth.
You might find you get more sales from
talking about fat loss.
These things that you learn across your
business over time massively impact your
business over time. Again,
if you can take your conversions up by
making
your font bigger, suddenly your font
is bigger on every page.
If dark mode converts better for you,
dark mode on every page.
So by A/B split testing, and again,
increasing your conversions on your
landing
page is such an important thing because
same traffic, same posts, same emails, all
of the stuff above this remains the same.
The only thing that changes
is how many people buy.
Again, dark mode for me works better.
Fonts always make it a little bit too easy
to read.
Make sure that your text isn't too small.
So we've gone through content,
we've gone through landing pages,
we've gone through
squeeze pages. To close up,
we're now going to get into the questions,
the last few
ones.
We're going to probably go for another 15
minutes, and then we're going to
wrap it up, and you guys
are going to buy [clicks tongue]
my business mentorship because we've got
about 42
slots for the rest of the year,
then after that,
we're shutting the doors, brother.
Okay. El Carmeno De Santiago,
"How can I sell
without selling my online coaching
service?
How can I sell without selling my online
coaching service?
I have 20,000 followers,
but not getting much engagement to get
coaching."
Golden rule, never sell on social media.
We've got so many coaches
that put a link in their bio
and wonder why people aren't
queuing up at the door for them. Again,
it's really important that you guys do
utilize email marketing
and all of the things
that I'm saying because people just
do not buy from social media.
How many of you have actually bought
something from
your phone walking to the shops?
We need to get people on social media,
get their
email addresses,
and we actually need them at desktop,
similar to what I am now.
When I pay with my credit card,
at my desktop, when I buy things,
at my desktop,
when I'm paying off people's fucking
invoices that come to me,
it's at my desktop.
Getting people from their mobile
and putting them into a place where they
can
genuinely
action the point that we want,
really important.
Steve Moore Golf, "Do before
and afters work for promoting your
training?" It's not
before and afters that work,
it's transformations.
The point of this,
I worked with a bathroom company recently.
They do tiling for bathrooms.
Their content, their page,
their Instagram was
just full of people's bathrooms they'd
done.
They never showed the bathroom before.
Now, you show someone the bathroom before,
then after, it's a journey.
It's a story. Here's the bathroom before.
Here's the after.
Now, no one cares about that bathroom,
but do you know what they care about?
Their bathroom.
Do you know what they care about?
Their kitchen.
Their own journey.
So when you show a before and after,
people don't care about the other person
before and after, but
if you can tell it in a story,
if you can tell it in a
transformation,
people want the transformation.
When you show off a fat loss client,
they don't give a fuck about the fat loss
client.
They care about the transformation
that person had.
They are buying into that transformation.
So it's not just the before and after.
Steve Moore, I need you to find someone.
I need to transform a part of their game,
their short game, their long game, their
drive, whatever it is,
and by transforming
that part of their game, other people
that want the same transformation will
also buy in.
Jack the Ninja,
"Would paid ads be worth the return on
investment early on in
launching a personal brand?"
From getting the initial followers up, no.
I want to discover someone.
I don't want to pay dad.
I don't follow people from paid ads.
Bro, what you're doing here
is you're looking for a way around the
hard work.
You're looking for a way to buy your way
through eating shit, and I cannot advise
against it enough.
Kind of like putting accelerant on the
fire.
If it's early,
you do not have a fire to throw accelerant
on.
You've got to grow, bro, and organic,
in so many ways, is easier.
So many ways because you have to become a
certain level of
good to grow organically.
You can throw money at anything,
but you're so much
better off becoming a weapon organic
and then adding paid ads.
You cannot use paid ads to buy your way
through the beginning.
"Launching my second boat next week on a
pre-sale landing page.
Any advice on that?" Your sales will be
correlated with how many signups you get.
"Build my brand around my name, Cy Bakes,
or my brand,
Transformed Mindset?" Definitely your
name.
Transformed Mindset,
come on, that's not a good brand.
Cy Bakes is fine.
Jayesh,
"What do you recommend as a strategy to
turn gym class attendees into
clients?
I get great feedback from my classes,
thinking of low-cost group programs
starting Jan." No.
Mate, why do they do gym classes?
They don't want personal training.
This is why gym classes
are such a stupid thing to do for leads.
Some people might,
but most people do gym classes because
they've got no interest
in personal training.
They can't afford it,
so they do gym classes.
All the people that can afford PT
or want PT aren't going to go to a group
class.
You know what I mean?
I'm sorry.
Okay.
It's like opening a butcher's for
vegetarians.
I just don't see it working.
"Thoughts on lead quizzes?
Was it okay to use the landing
page?" I don't know what that is,
but sure. Quizzes do work pretty well.
I'm starting to experiment with ScoreApp.
I will report back on
that to people in the mentorship
when I know more.
"I help home bakers bake
and decorate cakes using easy,
simple methods, saving
time.
Struggling to fill my in-person classes.
Launching my online course soon.
Is your mentorship for me?" Yes,
because I think you should be on YouTube.
I think that if you crack YouTube-
You will dominate in this baking cake
industry. Lucy Lord, right?
She does my fucking head in as one of my
best friends because she will refuse to go
on YouTube.
My missus watches Andy cooks on YouTube.
Sometimes I think she spends more time in
front of him than me.
I cannot explain this enough.
Things like that do so well on YouTube
because people that
are interested in baking cakes,
YouTube will float that in
front of them because YouTube understands
what people watch on YouTube.
When you make a video about baking
or cooking,
it'll get put in front of people
that like baking and cooking.
"When it comes to online plans,
should I stick to 12-week transformations
or offer
the online coaching on a monthly basis?
Offer both to see which goes down best.
Before I buy,
I'd like to explain my situation, see
if you believe I'm ready for
your course,
or do you suggest a few more things to
upgrade my knowledge, social
media before your course?
Can I email you?" No.
Ara Gawk, it's on the landing page.
You click on the offer,
you read the landing page,
you get one of two decisions.
You think it's right or don't. Again,
I'm sorry, I'm not here to bend over
backwards to make you buy my shit.
If you don't feel compelled to join after
me just giving you two and a half hours,
I can't fucking help you.
I'm sorry,
but I'm just not going to do that.
So please don't email me.
I'm here for two and a half hours
showcasing all of my expertise.
I'm answering all those questions.
I'm taking time away from my son.
If I haven't done enough at this point
and given you a fucking discount to join,
then fuck off. I'm sorry.
In the nicest possible way.
I would be going against everything
that I said.
I did not come here to beg for your
fucking business.
I came here to prove
that I know what the fuck I'm on about.
The majority of people in this industry
haven't got a fucking clue.
There are 42 spaces
that I started at the beginning of the
call.
As soon as I finish them,
I'm shutting shop.
I'm not here to convince you.
They are convinced through my work,
not my emails.
Again, if I didn't make
that clear enough on this live stream,
I'm sorry.
"How can someone with a technician,
electrician,
plumber profession get into online
sales?" I'm not sure would be the answer
to that.
"I run a sports marketing agency helping
footballers land paid contracts in
Australia.
Would your mentorship be suitable for me?"
Same question as goes before,
I'm afraid. I think at this point,
two hours 20, I've loved doing
this. I'm going to go back to my son.
There's an offer in the description.
It's fucking too cheap for what you get,
if anything.
I'm pulling it the second we sell those 42
spaces.
Thank you very much for coming in,
tuning in, nearly 1,000 of you guys,
for the
remainder of the call. I hope
that you got some information out of that,
and to
the top 2% of people in
that pyramid attribution
that end up buying my shit,
I'll see you in the Discord a little bit
later when my missus gets home, and I've
got a few days of Discord to catch up on.
You guys have been fucking great.
Thanks for tuning in.
Buy my fucking shit or don't.
See you later.
Love you lots. Bye-bye.